美国华纳兄弟影片公司 出品
美国传奇影业公司 联合出品
美国DC漫画公司
-三个人到了  我们开工吧  -什么  就我们三个吗
- Three of a kind, let's do this. - That's it? Three guys?
还有两个在屋顶
Two guys on the roof.
每人分一份钱  要分五份  已经不少了
Every guy gets a share. Five shares is plenty.
是六份  别忘了策划这次行动的家伙
Six shares. Don't forget the guy who planned the job.
他以为他什么都不干还能分成吗
He thinks he can sit it out and still take a slice?
我知道为什么大家叫他"小丑"了
I know why they call him the Joker.
那么  为什么大家叫他"小丑"
So, why do they call him the Joker?
-听说他很会化妆  -化妆?
- I heard he wears makeup. - Makeup?
对  用来吓人的  知道吧  就像战妆
Yeah, to scare people. You know, war paint.
好了各位  举高双手  低下头去
All right, everybody, hands up, heads down!
我说了  举手  低头
I said, hands up, heads down!
走开  伙计  我要来取款了
Let's go, pal, I'm making a withdrawal here.
-我说了  举起手  -不要
- I said, hands up! - No!
找到了  无声警报器
Here comes the silent alarm.
看它接去哪里?
And there it goes.
头低下
Heads down!
好了  宝贝儿  你乖乖给我蹲下
All right, tootsie, you're taking a dive with me.
-趴下  我说了  趴下  -别杀我
- Down! I said, stay down there! - Don't hurt me!
有意思  它不是接通911
Funny, it didn't dial 911.
而是打给一个私人号码
It was trying to reach a private number.
-有问题吗  -没有  搞定了
- Is it a problem? - No, I'm done here.
蹲下  蹲下
Sit down! Down!
蹲下  我说了  蹲着别动
Down! I said, stay down there!
很显然  我们可不希望你们的双手做任何事
Obviously we don't want you doing anything with your hands...
除了抓往自己的性命以外
...other than holding on for dear life.
趴下  趴在地上别动
On the ground! Stay on the ground!
谁都不准动  所有人  趴下
Nobody make a move! Nobody! Stay down!
你们知不知道在抢谁的钱?
You have any idea who you're stealing from?
-你们这帮人死定了  -他子弹打光了  对吧
- You and your friends are dead. - He's out, right?
什么
What...?
你数学在哪儿学的?
Where did you learn to count?
他们给这门通了5000伏的高压电
They wired this thing up with like 5000 volts.
什么银行会做这种事
What kind of bank does that?
黑帮银行  我觉得小丑果真像他们说的那样疯狂
A Mob bank. I guess the Joker's as crazy as they say.
截警报的人呢
Where's the alarm guy?
老大告诉我  他搞定警报后就干掉他
Boss told me when the guy was done, I should take him out.
少分一份钱  对吧
One less share, right?
有趣了  他也是这么对我说的
Funny, he told me something similar.
什么  别  别
He what? No! No!
这可真是一大笔钱
That's a lot of money.
要是这个小丑真这么神
If this Joker guy was so smart,
就该让我们开辆大点的车来
he'd have had us bring a bigger car.
我打赌  小丑跟你说过
I'm betting the Joker told you
我们装完钱后  马上把我干掉
to kill me soon as we loaded the cash.
不  不  不  我要杀的是巴士司机
No, no, no, I kill the bus driver.
巴士司机?
Bus driver?
什么巴士司机
What bus driver?
放学了  该回家了
School's out. Time to go.
这家伙起不来了  是吧
That guy's not getting up, is he?
钱还真不少啊
That's a lot of money.
其他人都去哪儿了
What happened to the rest of the guys?
你自以为很聪明  是吗
You think you're smart, huh?
雇你们的那个家伙
The guy that hired youse...
他会用同样的手法来对付你的
...he'll just do the same to you.
这座城市里的罪犯向来都有信仰的
Oh, criminals in this town used to believe in things.
名声
Honor...
尊敬
...respect.
但看看你  你信奉什么
Look at you. What do you believe in, huh?
你信奉什么
What do you believe in?!
我相信  杀不死你的东西  只会让你
I believe whatever doesn't kill you simply makes you...
更加怪异
...stranger.
市长先生  您是为了清除本市的犯罪而被选举出来的
Mr. Mayor, you were elected in a campaign to clean up the city.
-您打算什么时候开始行动  -我已经开始行动了
- When are you gonna start? - I already have.
比如所谓的蝙蝠侠  很多人说他是在做好事
Like this Batman.We're hearing he's doing good,
罪犯们看到他都闻风丧胆
criminals are running scared.
不  伙计  我觉得今晚不行
No, man. I don't like it tonight.
怎么  你还这么迷信
What are you, superstitious?
你中六合彩的概率
You got more chance of
都比撞上他的概率要大得多
winning the Powerball than running into him.
那不是事实
That's not true.
我得到消息  我们重案组的人快要抓到他了
Our men in the Major Crimes Unit are close to an arrest.
嘿  乌尔茨  市长说你们快抓到蝙蝠侠了
Hey, Wuertz, mayor says you're closing in on the Batman.
调查还在进行之中
The investigation is ongoing.
清除犯罪  我们还有很长的路要走
The process of cleaning up the streets is a long one.
我曾经在竞选中曾说过...
I pledged in my campaign, uh, to have...
有没有想过再去看看你的妻子  警长
Ever intending to see your wife again, lieutenant?
我还以为你回去照顾你妈去了  警探
I thought you had to go look after your mother, detective.
已经把她送去住院了
Checked her back into the hospital.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
-他还没来?  -他经常不来的
- So he hasn't shown up? - He often doesn't.
但我想提醒大家  他就在那里
I like reminding everybody he's out there.
他为什么不来
Why wouldn't he come?
希望是
Hopefully...
因为他正忙着
...because he's busy.
我们带狗来就是为这个
That's why we bring dogs.
-我可爱的小王子  -求你了
- My little princes. - Please.
求你了  它们爬进我嘴里
Please, they're crawling in my mouth.
求你把它们弄出来
Please, I beg you, get them off.
看看你的药把我的客户搞成什么样了
Look what your drugs do to my customers.
买方责任自负
Buyer beware.
我告诉过你  我的药会让人觉得飘飘然
I told you my compound would take you places.
可我没说过是你理想中的那种效果
I never said they'd be places you wanted to go.
我的生意是靠回头客的
My business, repeat customers.
如果你不满意我的货  那你可以去找别人买啊
You don't like what I have to offer, you can buy from someone else.
前提是蝙蝠侠还留着其他卖家
Assuming Batman left anyone to buy from.
我的狗饿了
My dogs are hungry.
可惜只有你这一份人肉
Pity there's only one of you.
-什么  -那不是他
- What...? - That's not him.
赶紧放狗
Loose the dogs!
这个比较像了
That's more like it.
待机状态
威慑模式
别再让我再看到你们
Don't let me find you out here again.
-我们是想帮你  -我不需要帮助
- We're trying to help you. - I don't need help.
我可不这样认为
Not my diagnosis.
你哪儿来这样的权力
What gives you the right?
你和我们到底有什么区别
What's the difference between you and me?
我不穿曲棍球护胸
I'm not wearing hockey pads.
全部人后退
Everybody back now!
他就是喜欢抛头露面
He can't resist showing us his face.
他化妆到底是为了遮掩什么
What's he hiding under that makeup?
麻烦大家离开一下  好吗
Uh, can we get a minute, people, please?
又是他  其他人是谁
Him again. Who are the others?
另外一群小混混而已
Another bunch of smalltimers.
是我给你的做过记号的钞票
Some of the marked bills I gave you.
几周来我的人都在用那些钱跟他们买毒品
My detectives have been making drug buys with them.
这银行也在为毒贩黑帮洗钱  总共有5家
This bank was another drop for the Mob. That makes five.
-我们找到了他们这些黑钱的去向  -该行动了
- We found the bulk of their dirty cash. - Time to move in.
我们得同时突击所有的银行  用特种部队支援
We'd have to hit all banks simultaneously. SWAT teams, backup.
那这个小丑怎么办
What about this Joker guy?
要抓一个人还是整个黑帮?  他的事不急
One man or the entire Mob? He can wait.
新上任的地方检察官听到了风声  他也想参加
When the new DA hears about this, he'll want in.
-你相信他吗  -要不让他参与很难
- Do you trust him? - Be hard to keep him out.
听说他和你一样固执
I hear he's as stubborn as you are.
韦恩企业
私有财产
不得擅入
等韦恩庄园重建之后就好了
Be nice when Wayne Manor's rebuilt.
如果你不喜欢睡在庄园里
You can swap not sleeping in a penthouse...
你也可以来这里睡
...for not sleeping in a mansion.
你每次给自己缝伤口  都会弄得一团糟
Whenever you stitch yourself up, you do make a bloody mess.
是的  但吃一堑长一智嘛
Yeah. It makes me learn from my mistakes.
那现在你应该长了不少智了
You ought to be pretty knowledgeable by now, then.
我的护甲
My armor.
它太重了
I'm carrying too much weight.
我想要轻便些  方便行动
I need to be... I need to be faster.
我想福克斯先生可以搞定
I'm sure Mr. Fox can oblige.
-你被老虎咬了吗?  -一只狗而已
- Did you get mauled by a tiger? - It was a dog.
-什么  -一只大狗
- Huh? - It was a big dog.
昨晚模仿者更多了  阿尔弗雷德  他们还带着枪
There were more copycats last night, Alfred, with guns.
你为什么不雇他们几个  自己周末放个假呢
Why not hire them, take the weekend off?
这根本不是我想要的结果
That wasn't exactly what I had in mind...
-虽然我是说过要启发人们  -我知道
- ...when I said I wanted to inspire people. - I know.
但事情总算往好的方面在发展
But things have improved.
看看新上任的地方检察官
Look at the new district attorney.
我有留意
I am, closely.
我得知道他是否值得相信
Need to know if he can be trusted.
你感兴趣的是他的为人  还是他的社交圈?
Are you interested in his character or his social circle?
瑞秋想跟谁在一起那是她的事
Who Rachel spends her time with is her business.
我想我休假的时候你没派人踪我吧
I trust you don't have me followed on my day off.
如果你真的休假  也许我会的
If you ever took one, I might.
快到你的极限了  韦恩少爷
Know your limits, Master Wayne.
蝙蝠侠是没有极限的
Batman has no limits.
-但您有  先生  -好吧  那还是不知道为好
- Well, you do, sir. - Well, can't afford to know them.
可哪一天等您发现了  你又会怎样
And what's gonna happen on the day that you find out?
我知道你会很得意地说  "我早告诉过你了"
We all know how much you like to say "I told you so."
真有那一天的话  韦恩少爷  我也不愿这么说的
On that day, Master Wayne, even I won't want to.
很可能
Probably.
抱歉各位  我来晚了
Sorry I'm late, folks.
-你去哪儿了  -你在担心要代我主控了吗
- Where were you? - Worried you'd have to step up?
-哈维  这些东西我都倒背如流了  -那好吧
- Harvey, I know these briefs backwards. - Well, then...
公平起见
...fair's fair.
正面  我来  背面  归你管
Heads, I'll take it. Tails, he's all yours.
你想扔硬币来决定谁来担任主控官吗
Yeah? You wanna flip a coin to see who leads?
这可是我老爸的幸运硬币
My father's lucky coin.
我还记得  我们第一次约会也是它决定的
As I recall, it got me my first date with you.
我可不会让那种事取决于运气的
I wouldn't leave something like that up to chance.
我也不会  我是自己创造运气
I don't. I make my own luck.
全体起立  尊敬的弗利尔法官入庭
All rise. The Honorable Judge Freel presiding.
我以为地方检察官只负责和市长打打高尔夫之类
I thought the DA just played golf with the mayor.
1:30才开球
Teeoff's 1:30.
在这之前有足够时间把你定罪  萨利
More than enough time to put you away for life, Sally.
卡麦·法康尼被关进了阿卡姆精神病院
With Carmine Falcone in Arkham...
一定会有人出来接手他所谓的"家族"
...someone must have stepped up to run the so-called family.
那个人今天在庭上吗
Is that man in this courtroom today?
-你能向我们指出他吗  -你赢了  长官
- Could you identify him for us, please? - You win, counselor.
那个人就是我
It was me.
我有你宣誓过的证词  你说这个人
I have a sworn statement from you that this man...
萨尔瓦多·马若尼  是法康尼家族的新领导人
...Salvatore Maroni, is the new head of the Falcone crime family.
马若尼  他是个替死鬼  我才是组织的首脑
Maroni? He's a fall guy. I'm the brains of the organization.
-肃静  -我申请将证人定为敌意证人
- Order. - Permission to treat the witness as hostile?
-批准  -敌意吗  我让你看看什么是敌意
- Granted. - Hostile? I'll show you hostile!
碳化纤维  28口径  中国制造
Carbon fiber, .28 caliber, made in China.
马若尼先生  如果你想刺杀公务人员
If you wanna kill a public servant, Mr. Maroni,
我建议你买美国货
I recommend you buy American.
-带他出去  -法官大人  我还没问完呢
- Get him out of here. - But, Your Honor, I'm not done.
我们没有办法把那枪
We'll never be able to link the gun
和马若尼拉上关系  我们不能起诉他
to Maroni, so we can't charge him.
但他们企图杀你  说明我们戳到了痛处
But they're trying to kill you, means we're getting to them.
很高兴你这么振奋  瑞秋  顺便说一下我确实没事
I'm glad you're so pleased, Rachel. I'm fine, by the way.
得了  哈维  你是在哥谭市做检察官
Come on, Harvey. You're Gotham's DA.
如果没人想杀你  说明你的工作没做好
You're not getting shot at, you're not doing your job right.
但你知道
But, you know...
要是你说你受惊了
...if you said you were rattled,
我们今天可以放个假
we could take the rest of the day off.
不行  我约了重案组的头儿在这里见面
Can't. I dragged the head of the Major Crimes Unit down here.
吉姆·戈登吗  他是我朋友  对他客气点
Oh, Jim Gordon? He's a friend, actually. Try to be nice.
听说你在庭上被翻供了
I hear you got a hell of a right cross.
可惜让萨利继续逍遥法外了
It's a shame Sal's going to walk.
是的  不过黑帮的优点是
Yeah, well, good thing about the Mob
总会给你第二次机会来逮他们
is they keep giving you second chances.
低辐射标记过的钞票
Lightly irradiated bills.
对城市警察来说这玩意儿真高级  有帮手?
Fancy stuff for a city cop. Have help?
我们和各个部门都有联络...
We liaise with various agencies...
省省吧  戈顿  我要见他
Save it, Gordon. I wanna meet him.
官方指示是
Official policy is to
要当场逮捕自称蝙蝠侠的义务警员
arrest the vigilante known as Batman on sight.
那重案组大楼顶上的探照灯是怎么回事
Mm-hm. What about that floodlight on the top of MCU?
如果您对设备故障有疑问的话
If you got problems with malfunctioning equipment...
我建议您联系市政建设部门  长官
...I suggest you take them up with Maintenance, counselor.
我把哥谭市所有洗黑钱的都关进了监狱
I've put every money launderer in Gotham behind bars...
但黑帮分子还是有办法洗钱
...but the Mob is still getting its money out.
我想你和你的朋友已经找到了城中最后的关键所在
I think you and your friend have found the last game in town.
你们想打击他们的要害  他们的金库
You're trying to hit them where it hurts, their wallets.
很勇敢
It's bold.
可以算上我一个吗
You gonna count me in?
在这个城市
In this town,
一件事情  知道的人越少  行动就越安全
the fewer people know something, the safer the operation.
我不希望你搞什么"特别小组"
I don't like that you got your own special unit...
尤其是你那边的警察  我全部都在内务部调查过
...and it's full of cops I investigated at Internal Affairs.
要是我不和那些你调查过的警察共事
If I didn't work with cops you'd investigated while at IA...
我就要孤军奋战了
...I'd be working alone.
我不懂什么理想主义的政治观念
I don't get political points for being an idealist.
我只是人尽其用而已
I do the best I can with what I have.
你要我签发搜查令
You want me to back warrants
用来搜查五家银行
for search and seizure on five banks...
却不告诉我要找的是什么
...without telling me what we're after.
我可以告诉你银行的名字
I can give you the names of the banks.
这是个好的开始
Well, that's a start.
我可以给你开搜查令  但我要你相信我
I'll get you your warrants, but I want your trust.
你不需要跟我来这一套  登特
Oh, you don't have to sell me, Dent.
我们都清楚  你是哥谭的光明骑士
We all know you're Gotham's white knight.
好吧  可我听说
Yeah, well, I heard
在重案组他们给我起了另一个绰号
they have a different name for me down at MCU.
这我就不知道了
I wouldn't know about that.
在中国  刘氏证券投资代表了高增长的新兴力量
In China, Lau Security Investments stands for dynamic new growth.
与中国企业合资将会使韦恩企业变得更加强大
A joint Chinese venture with Wayne Enterprises will be a powerhouse.
好的  刘先生
Well, Mr. Lau...
我谨代表董事会其他成员
...I speak for the rest of the board...
以及韦恩先生  来表达我们的激动之情
...and Mr. Wayne, in expressing our own excitement.
先生  我知道韦恩先生
Sir, I know Mr. Wayne is curious
很关心他的信托基金是怎么运作的
about how his trust fund gets replenished...
但老实说  这太令人尴尬了
...but, frankly, this is embarrassing.
瑞斯先生  你操心工作的事就行了
You worry about the diligence, Mr. Reese.
我来操心布鲁斯·韦恩好了
I'll worry about Bruce Wayne.
已经做完了
It's done.
数据没问题
The numbers are solid.
那就再算一遍
Do them again.
我们也不想信托基金出任何差池吧
Wouldn't want the trust fund to run out, now, would we?
又是漫长的一夜?
Another long night?
这次并购是你的主意  咨询人员都很认可
This joint venture was your idea, and the consultants love it.
但我不太放心
But I'm not convinced.
刘的公司每年都以8%的速度增长  跟时钟一样准
Lau's company has grown by 8 percent annually like clockwork.
他的收入来源一定有猫腻
His revenue stream must be off the books...
可能还是非法的
...maybe even illegal.
好吧  交易取消
Okay. Cancel the deal.
你早知道了
You already knew.
我只想借机查下他们的帐
Just needed a closer look at their books.
还有什么能为您效劳的吗
Anything else you can trouble me for?
我要一件新衣服
I need a new suit.
三粒扣子的西装是90年代的款式了  韦恩先生
Yeah. Three buttons is a little '90s, Mr. Wayne.
我要的不是时尚  福克斯先生  是功能
I'm not talking fashion, Mr. Fox, so much as function.
你希望头部可以自由转动
You wanna be able to turn your head.
这样倒车的时候会轻松很多
Sure make backing out of the driveway easier.
我来想想办法
I'll see what I can do.
我花了三个星期才订到位子
Took three weeks to get a reservation here.
还得透露给他们说我在政府工作
I had to tell them I work for the government.
-真的吗  -卫生署的人还帮我托了关系
- Really? - Health inspector's not afraid to pull strings.
瑞秋  真巧
Rachel. Fancy that.
是啊  布鲁斯  真巧
Yeah, Bruce. Fancy that.
瑞秋  这是娜塔莎  娜塔莎  这是瑞秋
Rachel, Natascha. Natascha, Rachel.
娜塔莎 你是那个...
Natascha. Are you the prima...?
莫斯科芭蕾舞团的首席芭蕾舞演员
Prima ballerina for the Moscow Ballet.
哈维下周准备带我去看呢
Wow. Harvey's taking me next week.
是吗  你也喜欢芭蕾?
Really? So you're into ballet?
布鲁斯  这是哈维·登特
Bruce. This is Harvey Dent.
大名鼎鼎的布鲁斯·韦恩  瑞秋把你的事都告诉我了
The famous Bruce Wayne. Rachel's told me everything about you.
希望她没全说
I certainly hope not.
那么  让我们拼成一桌吧
So, let's put a couple tables together.
我想他们不会同意吧
I'm not sure that they'll let us.
会同意的  我是这里的老板
Oh, they should. I own the place.
你们怎么会想在这样的城市里养孩子?
How could you want to raise children in a city like this?
我就是在这里长大的  不是很好吗
Well, I was raised here. I turned out okay.
韦恩庄园在本市的版图里吗？
Is Wayne Manor in the city limits?
是否在界内吗  当然
The Palisades? Sure.
作为一个新上任的检察官
You know, as our new DA,
你得清楚你的权利范围有多大
you might wanna figure out where your jurisdiction ends.
我想说的是  这个城市
I'm talking about the kind of city
把一个蒙面义警给偶像化了
that idolizes a masked vigilante.
哥谭市以此而荣
Gotham City is proud of
一个普通人站出来  为正义而战
an ordinary citizen standing up for what's right.
哥谭需要像你这样通过民主选举选出来的英雄
Gotham needs heroes like you, elected officials...
而不是一个认为自己能凌驾于法律之上的人
...not a man who thinks he's above the law.
蝙蝠侠是由谁任命的?
Who appointed the Batman?
是我们  正因为我们
We did. All of us who stood
都放手不管  放任那些人渣掌控我们的城市
by and let scum take control of our city.
但这就是民主  哈维
But this is a democracy, Harvey.
在敌人已经兵临城下之时
When their enemies were at the gates...
罗马人暂停了他们的民主
...the Romans would suspend
任命一个人来保卫他们的城市
democracy and appoint one man to protect the city.
这不是一项荣誉  而是对公众所尽的义务
It wasn't considered an honor, it was a public service.
哈维  最后一个被任命
Harvey, the last man that they appointed
保卫城市的人就是凯撒
to protect the republic was named Caesar...
-而他再也没有交还出自己的权力  -好吧  好吧
- ...and he never gave up his power. - Okay, fine.
你要么像英雄一样死去
You either die a hero...
要么就苟活下去  直到自己堕入恶人之伍
...or you live long enough to see yourself become the villain.
不论蝙蝠侠是谁
Whoever the Batman is,
他不会愿意就这么过一辈子
he doesn't wanna do this for the rest of his life.
他怎么受得了  蝙蝠侠
How could he? Batman is
正希望有人能继承他的衣钵
looking for someone to take up his mantle.
像你这样的人吗  登特先生?
Someone like you, Mr. Dent?
也许吧  如果我能胜任
Maybe. If I'm up to it.
也许哈维·登特就是那披斗篷的骑士
What if Harvey Dent is the Caped Crusader?
我要是每天晚上都溜出去
If I were sneaking out every night,
肯定早就被人发现了
someone would've noticed by now.
我被你说服了  登特  我给你办个筹资活动
Well, I'm sold, Dent, and I'm gonna throw you a fundraiser.
你的好意我心领了  可我最近三年都不准备参选
That's nice, but I'm not up for reelection for three years.
我想你还没明白
No, you don't understand.
我为你举办一次筹资活动
One fundraiser with my pals...
你以后都不需要掏一分钱了
...you'll never need another cent.
这是什么玩意儿
What the hell is this?
你们都知道  我们的一部分钱被偷了
As you're all aware, one of our deposits was stolen.
相对来说数目不大  6800万
A relatively small amount, 68 million.
谁会蠢到在我们头上动土?
Who's stupid enough to steal from us?
穿着便宜的紫色道具服  化着妆的不入流的混混
Two-bit wackjob, wears a cheap purple suit and makeup.
不用担心他  无名小卒而已
He's not the problem. He's a nobody.
棘手的是  警察追踪到了我们的钱
The problem is our money being tracked by the cops.
多亏了马若尼先生安插的线人
Thanks to Mr. Maroni's well-placed sources...
我们已经知道警察
...we know that police have indeed
通过被标记的钞票查到了银行
identified our banks using marked bills...
他们计划今天就查抄你们那里
...and are planning to seize your funds today.
鉴于热心肠的新任检察官
And since the enthusiastic new DA
已经逮捕了我其他的竞争者
has put all my competitors out of business...
-你们现在只得靠我了  -你有什么建议
- ...I'm your only option. - So, what are you proposing?
把所有钱转移到一个安全的地方  不是银行
Moving all deposits to one secure location, not a bank.
-那是哪里?  -只有我知道
- Where, then? - No one can know but me.
如果你们当中有一个人向警察告了密
If the police were to gain leverage over one of you...
那大家的钱都得打水漂了
...everyone's money would be at stake.
他们为什么对付不了你
What stop them getting to you?
我正前往香港  登特根本管不到那里
I go to Hong Kong, far from Dent's jurisdiction...
中国也不会同意引渡自己的公民
...and the Chinese will not extradite one of their own.
钱什么时候能够转走
How soon can you move the money?
已经转移了
I already have.
理由很明显  我来不及征得你们的同意
For obvious reasons, I couldn't wait for your permission.
请诸位放心  你们的钱很安全
Rest assured, your money is safe.
我还觉得我的笑话够冷了呢
And I thought my jokes were bad.
给我个理由  为什么我不应该把你的头拧下来
Give me one reason why I shouldn't have my boy pull your head off.
我表演个魔术怎么样
How about a magic trick?
我能让这支铅笔消失
I'm gonna make this pencil disappear.
它...
It's...
消失了
It's gone.
顺便说下  这衣服可不便宜
Oh, and by the way, the suit, it wasn't cheap.
-你们应该知道  是用你们的钱买的  -坐下
- You ought to know, you bought it. - Sit.
我想听听他的建议
I want to hear proposition.
我们回想一年多以前
Let's wind the clocks back a year.
这些警察  律师  都不敢招惹你们
These cops and lawyers wouldn't dare cross any of you.
我意思是  现在怎么了
I mean, what happened?
难道你们都被阉了吗
Did your balls drop off? Hm?
你看  像我这样的人
You see, a guy like me...
-怪胎  -真他妈对
- A freak. - Damn right.
像我这样的人  听着
A guy like me... Look, listen.
我知道你们为什么把你们这个小型的
I know why you choose to have your little, ahem...
群体互助心理治疗放在白天举行
...group-therapy sessions in broad daylight.
我知道为什么你们晚上不敢出门
I know why you're afraid to go out at night.
因为蝙蝠侠
The Batman.
蝙蝠侠让哥谭人发现你们的真面目  真不幸
See, Batman has shown Gotham your true colors, unfortunately.
登特  他只是个开始
Dent, he's just the beginning.
还有电视里的这个人所谓的计划
And as for the television's so-called plan...
蝙蝠侠是没有界限的
...Batman has no jurisdiction.
他会找到他  再让他全盘托出的
He'll find him and make him squeal.
会泄密的人我一眼就能看出来
I know the squealers when I see them...
而这家伙...
...and...
那你有什么建议
What do you propose?
很简单  我们...杀了蝙蝠侠
It's simple. We, uh, kill the Batman.
这么简单的话  你怎么还不动手
If it's so simple, why haven't you done it already?
对于擅长的事情  当然不能免费去做
If you're good at something, never do it for free.
你想要多少
How much you want?
一半
Uh, half.
-你疯了  -不  我没有
You're crazy. - No, I'm not.
我才没有
No, I'm not.
如果我们现在还不能达成协议...
If we don't deal with this now...
很快...
...soon...
这里的小甘宝
...little Gambol here
就连个子儿都给不了他奶奶了
won't be able to get a nickel for his grandma.
我受够这个小丑了
Enough from the clown!
我们还是别冒火的好
Ah, ta-ta-ta. Let's not blow...
-妈的  -这可不值得啊
- Shit! - ...this out of proportion.
你以为你偷完我们  还可以一走了之吗
You think you can steal from us and just walk away?
-没错  -我现在就放话
- Yeah. - I'm putting the word out.
悬赏50万取小丑的项上人头
Five hundred grand for this clown dead.
活捉就赏100万  这样我就能先教教他礼数
A million alive, so I can teach him some manners first.
好吧  听着  你们可以给我打个电话
All right. So, listen, why don't you give me a call...
当你想更认真地考虑事情状况的时候
...when you wanna start taking things a little more seriously?
这是我的名片
Here's my card.
你这人还真难联系
You're a hard man to reach.
刘已经出发回香港了
Lau's halfway to Hong Kong.
如果你早开口的话  我就扣下他的护照了
If you'd have asked, I could have taken his passport.
我说了要算我一个的
I told you to keep me in the loop.
保险库里头只剩下被标记的钞票
All that was left in the vaults were marked bills.
他们早知道我们要来  你的手下一牵涉进来就...
They knew we were coming. As soon as your office got involved...
我的手下?
My office?
你整天坐在那儿
You're sitting down there
和乌尔茨还有雷米兹这样的人渣共事  你还敢说...
with scum like Wuertz and Ramirez and you're talking...
是啊  我破的诈骗案把你那些菜鸟吓坏了吧
Oh, yeah. I almost had your rookie cold on a racketeering beat.
不要试图掩盖事实
Don't try and cloud the fact that
很明显马若尼在你手下安排了内线  登特
clearly Maroni's got people in your office, Dent.
我们得让刘回来
We need Lau back...
但无论如何中国政府都不会同意引渡本国公民
...but the Chinese won't extradite a national under any circumstances.
我要是带他回来  你能让他开口吗
If I get him to you, can you get him to talk?
我都能让他唱歌的
I'll get him to sing.
接下来要追寻暴徒们的毕生积蓄
We're going after the Mob's life savings.
情况会日益险恶
Things will get ugly.
警长  我任职时就了解其中的风险了
I knew the risk when I took this job, lieutenant.
你要怎么带他回...
How will you get him back, any...?
他经常这样
He does that.
在我通知他们交易取消前  我们的中国朋友就走了
Our Chinese friends left town before I could tell them the deal was off.
好吧  我猜你一直都想去香港看看吧
Well, I'm sure that you've always wanted to go to Hong Kong.
打个电话不就行了
What's wrong with a phone call?
我觉得刘先生值得我们特殊对待
I think Mr. Lau deserves a more personal touch.
好了  要想在高空跳跃
Now, for high-altitude jumps,
你需要用到氧气和平衡装置
you're going to need oxygen and stabilizers.
我不得不说  和你平时的要求比
Well, I must say, compared to your usual requests...
跳下飞机还真是直截了当
...jumping out of an airplane is pretty straightforward.
那怎么回到飞机上呢？
What about getting back into the plane?
-我建议选个好旅行社  -要中途不着陆的
- I'd recommend a good travel agent. - Without it landing.
这才像样  韦恩先生
Now, that's more like it, Mr. Wayne.
中情局在六十年代有个项目...
The CIA had a program back in the '60s...
来把他们的人撤出危险地带  名叫"天钩"
...for getting their people out of hot spots called Sky Hook.
-我们可以研究下  -好的
- We could look into that. - Yeah.
好的  现在...
Okay. Now...
钛合金加强型凯夫拉盔甲
Hardened Kevlar plates
加上三编织纤维以加强灵活性
over titanium-dipped tri-weave fibers for flexibility.
你的活动会更轻  更快  更灵活
You'll be lighter, faster, more agile.
也许你应该先看看使用说明
Perhaps you should read the instructions first?
-是啊  -不过  有得必有失
- Yeah. - Now, there is a tradeoff.
护甲板的多片分离
Separation of the plates
将降低你对刀枪袭击的防御力
makes you more vulnerable to knives and gunfire.
我们不能指望凡事都两全其美  不是吗
We wouldn't wanna make things too easy, now, would we?
它能抵御狗的袭击吗
How will it hold up against dogs?
罗威那犬还是吉娃娃?
We talking rottweilers or Chihuahuas?
用来防猫抓倒是挺好用
Should do fine against cats.
我在亚利桑那州找到了
I found one in Arizona.
一个不错的家伙  说他可以
A very nice man said he could
在一周内起飞  而且要现金付款
have it up and running in a week, and he takes cash.
-机组人员呢  -韩国的走私犯
- What about the flight crew? - South Korean smugglers.
他们能避开雷达监测飞到平壤
They run flights into Pyongyang, below radar.
-你想好不在场托辞了吗  -当然
- Did you think of an alibi? - Oh, yes.
演出取消
爱之舟：亿万富翁携俄罗斯芭蕾舞团出海游玩
先生  我想这就是您的飞机了
I believe this is your plane, sir.
阿尔弗雷德  你看起来很累啊  没我你能搞定吗
You look tired, Alfred. You'll be all right without me?
如果你能教我怎么用俄语说
If you can tell me the Russian
"涂好你那该死的防晒油"
for "Apply your own bloody suntan lotion."
嘿  甘宝  有人来找你
Yo, Gambol, somebody here for you.
他们说已经把小丑干掉了
They say they've just killed the Joker.
他们把尸体带来了
They brought the body.
好  死的 赏金就是50万
So, dead, that's 500.
那活的呢
How about alive? Hm?
想知道我这些伤疤怎么来的吗
You wanna know how I got these scars?
我父亲是个...
My father was...
酒鬼...
...A drinker...
恶魔...
...and a fiend.
有天晚上他发酒疯比往常还要严重
And one night, he goes off crazier than usual.
妈妈只好拿出厨房的菜刀自卫
Mommy gets the kitchen knife to defend herself.
他不喜欢这样...
He doesn't like that...
一点也不
...not one bit.
于是  我就看着...
So, me watching...
他一边用刀捅她  还一边哈哈大笑
...he takes the knife to her, laughing while he does it.
他转向我  对我说
He turns to me and he says:
"为什么这么严肃？"
"Why so serious?"
他举着刀朝我走来
He comes at me with the knife.
"为什么这么严肃？"
"Why so serious?"
他把刀刃插进我嘴里
He sticks the blade in my mouth.
"让我们来画个笑脸吧"
"Let's put a smile on that face."
然后...
And...
为什么这么严肃？
Why so serious?
现在呢...
Now...
我们的业务还不大
...our operation is small...
但对于强劲地开扩市场
...but there is a lot of potential...
还是很有发展潜力的
...for aggressive expansion.
所以  你们当中哪位好先生愿意加入我们呢
So which of you fine gentlemen would like to join our team?
哦  现在只剩一个名额了  所以我们得来个...
Oh. There's only one spot open right now, so we're gonna have...
选拔
...tryouts.
尽快解决
Make it fast.
福克斯先生  欢迎来到香港
Welcome to Hong Kong, Mr. Fox.
很遗憾刘先生今天不能亲自前来迎接
Mr. Lau regrets he is unable to greet you in person today.
我理解
I understand.
为了安全起见
For security purposes,
请您暂时上交手您的手机
I'm gonna have to ask you to check in your mobile.
当然可以
Of course.
我非常抱歉在谈判期间就离开了哥谭
I must apologize for leaving Gotham in the middle of our negotiations.
我与哥谭警方发生了点误会
This misunderstanding with the Gotham police force...
-我不能让其威胁到我的公司  -当然
- ...I couldn't let it threaten my company. - Of course.
相信您这样声誉在望的人会理解的
A businessman of your stature will understand and...
既然您来了  我们就能继续谈了
...with you here now, we can continue.
好吧  很感激您这样高规格
Well, I do appreciate you bringing me out here
来接待我  刘先生  但...
in such style, Mr. Lau, but I re...
这里不允许带手机的
We do not allow cell phones in here.
抱歉  都忘了我还带着它
I'm sorry. Forgot I had it.
不  我来是想告诉您
No, I really came to tell you
我们之间的合作得暂时搁置了
that our business deal has to be put on hold.
我们没法承担被查出和你们交易的后果
You see, we can't afford to be seen to do business with...
不管你们被指控什么
...whatever it is you're accused of being.
我相信您这样声誉在望的人也能理解
I'm sure a businessman of your stature will understand.
我觉得  福克斯先生  您只要打个电话就行了
I think, Mr. Fox, a simple phone call might have sufficed.
韦恩先生并不想让您
Mr. Wayne didn't want you
以为他是在故意浪费您的时间
to think he was deliberately wasting your time.
只是碰巧浪费一下罢了
Just accidentally wasting it.
说得好  刘先生  "碰巧"  非常好
That's very good, Mr. Lau. "Accidentally." Very good.
先生
Hey, sir.
山顶缆车上的风景应该会更好
There's a better view from the peak tram.
刘那边的风景如何
How's the view from LSI Holdings?
戒备森严
Restricted.
刘在里面是高枕无忧
Lau is holed up in there good and tight.
-这是什么  -我让研发部设计的
- What's this? - I had R & D work it up.
可以发射高频脉冲
Sends out a high-frequency pulse...
根据记录的反应时间绘制周边环境
...records the response time for mapping an environment.
声纳  就像...
Sonar. Just like a...
潜水艇  韦恩先生  就像潜水艇
Submarine, Mr. Wayne. Like a submarine.
-另一台呢  -都放好了
- And the other device? - It's in place.
韦恩先生?
Mr. Wayne?
祝你好运
Good luck.
好的 好的
去看一看
这里是楼下大堂 听见吗
警察在哪儿
他们要来了
我们已经付过他们钱了 他们还不来
啊 放手
放手 不要
我什么都给你 给我放手
别开枪
请送至 戈登警长
听着  把钱交出来  我们才能谈条件
Look, give us the money and we'll talk about making a deal.
那些钱  是我还活着的唯一原因
The money is the only reason I'm still alive.
哦  你是说  当他们发觉你帮了我们
Oh, you mean, when they find out that you've helped us,
就会杀了你吗
they're gonna kill you?
-你在威胁我的当事人吗  -不
- Are you threatening my client? - No.
我只是认定你的当事人
I'm just assuming your client's
会配合我们的调查
cooperation with this investigation.
换谁都会同意的
As will everyone.
不说吗  好吧
No? Okay.
享受你的监狱时光吧  刘先生
Enjoy your time in County, Mr. Lau.
等等
Wait!
我不会把钱给你
I won't give you the money...
但我能给你客户名单  所有客户
...but I will give you my clients, all of them.
你充其量就是个会计
You were a glorified accountant.
你凭什么说你掌握了所有人的名单呢
What could you possibly have on all of them that we could charge?
我精于计算  他们的投资都由我打理
I'm good with calculation. I handled all their investments.
全在我手上
One big pot.
搞定
Got it.
稍等一下
One minute.
RICO法案  如果他们集中了资金
RICO. If they pooled their money,
RICO法案：《反诈骗腐败组织集团犯罪法》
我们就能以合谋犯罪指控他们
we can charge them as one criminal conspiracy.
指控他们什么
Charge them with what?
在这种案例中
In a RICO case,
如果你能因罪指控他们中的一人...
if you can charge one of conspiracy with a felony...
就能以此指控他们所有人  好极了
You can charge all of with it. That's great.
刘先生
Mr. Lau.
关于这笔共有资金你了解多少呢
What kind of details do you have about this communal fund?
-是账簿呢...  -我要外交豁免 人身保护...
- Ledgers...? - Immunity, protection...
返回香港的特许航班
...A chartered plane back to Hong Kong.
等你出庭作证后都好说
After you testify in open court.
我很好奇  等你的客户都被抓了
I'm just curious. With all your clients locked up...
这些钱会被如何处理呢
...what's gonna happen with all that money?
我说过  我精于计算
Like I said, I'm good with calculation.
不能带他去监狱  我要留他在这儿的拘留室里
He can't go to County. I'll keep him here in the holding cells.
这算什么  戈登  你的堡垒吗
What is this, Gordon, your fortress?
那监狱的人你信得过吗
Well, you trust them over at County?
我更不信任这里的人
I don't trust them here.
刘必须留下
Lau stays.
好吧  我不清楚刘先生的行程安排
Well, I don't know about Mr. Lau's travel arrangements,
不过我很高兴他回来了
but I'm sure glad he's back.
放话出去  我们要雇用小丑
Put word out. We hire the clown.
他说得对  我们得解决掉实际问题
He was right. We have to fix real problem.
蝙蝠侠
Batman.
我不知道任何参与行动
I'm not aware of any participation...
我们的小子还挺上镜的
Our boy looks good on the tube.
你确定要在我的弟兄面前给我难堪吗
You sure you wanna embarrass me in front of my friends?
哦  别担心  他们也一样被捕了
Oh, don't worry. They're coming too.
祝旅途愉快  明年见
Have a nice trip. See you next fall.
712项敲诈案
Seven hundred twelve counts of extortion.
849项勒索案
Eight hundred and forty-nine counts of racketeering.
246项诈骗案
Two hundred and forty-six counts of fraud.
87项谋杀案
Eighty-seven counts of conspiracy murder.
527项妨碍司法公正案
Five hundred and twenty-seven counts of obstruction of justice.
被告有什么要辩护的
How do the defendants plead?
请保持秩序
Order in the court.
一下子控告549个罪犯
Five hundred and forty-nine criminals at once.
你是怎么说服瑟利罗来参与这场闹剧的
How did you convince Surrillo to hear this farce?
她和我都有强烈的正义感
She shares my enthusiasm for justice.
毕竟她是个法官
After all, she is a judge.
就算你磨薄嘴皮  说服瑟利罗对他们定罪
Even if you blow enough smoke to get convictions out of Surrillo
你收到的上诉数量也肯定会破记录
...you're gonna set a new record at appeals.
没关系  高层人物肯定会被保释
It won't matter. The head guys make bail, sure.
但是下面的人  他们不行
But the midlevel guys, they can't.
他们可等不到庭审和上诉
They can't afford to be off the streets.
肯定会用减刑这样的条件来做交易
They'll cut deals that include some jail time.
想想吧  18个月没有犯罪日子
Think of all you could do with 18 months of clean streets.
-市长先生  你不能...  -不  你们都出去吧
- Mr. Mayor, you can't... - No, get out. Both of you.
坐吧
Sit down.
民众喜欢你  这是你或许能成功的唯一原因
The public likes you. That's the only reason that this might fly.
不过你就要准备接招了
But that means it's on you.
他们都会找上你的  不止是那些黑帮
They're all gonna come after you now, and not just the Mob.
政治家  记者  警察
Politicians, journalists, cops.
所有你触动了利益的人
Anyone whose wallet's about to get lighter.
你准备好了吗  最好准备好了
Are you up to it? You'd better be.
如果他们抓到你的任何把柄...
Because they get anything on you...
...还有那些罪犯刑满释放之后
...and those criminals are back on the streets,
最先找上的就是你和我
followed swiftly by you and me.
天啊
Jesus!
真正的蝙蝠侠
请站出来好吗？
先生  我想你的资金筹备将会很成功的
I think your fundraiser will be a great success, sir.
你觉得我为什么会为哈维·登特举办宴会
And why do you think I wanna hold a party for Harvey Dent?
我猜还是那个原因
I assumed it was your usual reason
除了跟我打交道
for socializing beyond myself...
和打击哥谭罪犯外
...and the scum of Gotham's underbelly:
你都是为了打动道斯小姐
To try to impress Miss Dawes.
很有意思  可惜错了  实际上  是登特
Very droll, but very wrong. Actually, it's Dent.
警方公布了在尸体上发现的一段录像
Police released video footage found concealed on the body.
承受力差的观众请注意  以下镜头可能会引起不适
Sensitive viewers, be aware. The image is disturbing.
告诉大家你的名字
Tell them your name.
布莱恩·道格拉斯
Brian Douglas.
你真的是蝙蝠侠吗
And are you the real Batman?
-不是  -不是吗
- No. - No?
那你为什么打扮得和他一样
Then why do you dress up like him?
因为他是一个象征
Because he's a symbol that
鼓励我们不必害怕你这样的人渣
we don't have to be afraid of scum like you.
你应该怕  布莱恩  你真应该怕
Yeah. You do, Brian. You really do.
这么说你觉得蝙蝠侠让哥谭更加美好吗
So you think Batman's made Gotham a better place? Hm?
看着我
Look at me.
Look at me!
看  蝙蝠侠所造就的哥谭是如此疯狂
You see, this is how crazy Batman's made Gotham.
要想让哥谭治安有序
You want order in Gotham...
蝙蝠侠必须摘下面具  去投案自首
...Batman must take off his mask and turn himself in.
只要他一天不自首  就会一直有人死
Oh, and every day he doesn't, people will die.
从今晚开始
Starting tonight.
我言出必行
I'm a man of my word.
哈维·登特  罪犯们的噩梦
Harvey Dent, scourge of the underworld...
被筹款晚会的人群吓傻了
...scared stiff by the trust-fund brigade.
-我一会儿回来  -瑞秋
- I'll be back. - Rachel.
登特先生  要来点酒壮胆吗
A little liquid courage, Mr. Dent?
-谢谢  你是阿尔弗雷德  对吗  -是的  先生
- Thank you. Alfred, right? - That's right, sir.
瑞秋经常说起你  听说你是看着她长大的
Rachel talks about you all the time. You've known her whole life.
那还不至于  先生
Not yet, sir.
她有没有精神错乱的前男友需要我当心的吗
Any psychotic ex-boyfriends I should be aware of?
哦  你绝对想不到
Oh, you have no idea.
对不起  我来晚了
I'm sorry that I'm late.
很高兴看到大家没有我就开始了
I'm glad to see that you all got started without me.
现在  哈维在哪儿呢  哪儿呢
Now, where is Harvey? Where...?
哈维·登特  风云人物啊
Harvey Dent, the man of the hour.
瑞秋·道斯在哪儿呢
Where's Rachel Dawes?
她是我交情最久的朋友  过来吧
She is my oldest friend. Come here.
当瑞秋第一次告诉我
When Rachel first told me
她在和哈维·登特约会时  我只想说
she was dating Harvey Dent, I had one thing to say:
"那糟糕的竞选广告里的那家伙"
"The guy from those God-awful campaign commercials?"
"我相信哈维·登特"  口号不错啊  哈维
"I believe in Harvey Dent." Yeah, nice slogan, Harvey.
但吸引了瑞秋的注意
But it caught Rachel's attention.
于是我也开始关注哈维
And then I started to pay attention to Harvey...
和他作为新检察官的所作所为
...and all that he's been doing as our new DA.
你知道吗
And you know what?
我相信哈维·登特
I believe in Harvey Dent.
我相信在他的守护下  哥谭能变得...
I believe that on his watch, Gotham can feel...
更加安全  更加乐观
...A little safer, a little more optimistic.
看看这张脸  这是哥谭光明未来的象征
Look at this face. This is the face of Gotham's bright future.
致哈维·登特  让我们听听他的心声
To Harvey Dent. Let's hear it for him.
哈维可能不是那么了解你...
Harvey may not know you well enough
所以他不知道你是在取笑他
to understand you're making fun of him...
-但我听出来了  -不  这是我的肺腑之言
- ...but I do. - No, I meant every word.
你记得那一天吗  你曾经告诉过我
You know that day that you once told me about when...
哥谭将有一天不再需要蝙蝠侠
...Gotham would no longer need Batman?
-这一天要来了  -布鲁斯
- It's coming. - Bruce.
你不能要我等待这天的到来
You can't ask me to wait for that.
不用等了  哈维就是那个英雄
It's happening now. Harvey is that hero.
他把半个市里的罪犯都关押起来了
He locked up half of the city's criminals,
而且没戴过什么面具
and he did it without wearing a mask.
哥谭需要有真面容的英雄
Gotham needs a hero with a face.
你办的宴会不错  韦恩  我想说
You can throw a party, Wayne, I'll give you that.
非常感谢
Thanks again.
介意我跟瑞秋聊会吗
You mind if I borrow Rachel?
警长  那张附在尸体上的扑克牌
Lieutenant, that joker card pinned to the body?
弗朗西斯鉴定出了三组DNA
Forensics found three sets of DNA.
-有匹配的吗?  -三组都匹配
- Any matches? - All three.
DNA分别属于瑟利罗法官  哈维·登特和劳博局长
The DNA belongs to Judge Surrillo, Harvey Dent and Commissioner Loeb.
小丑在告诉我们他的目标
The Joker's telling us who he's targeting.
派一队人前往瑟利罗家  通知乌尔茨去找登特
Get a unit over to Surrillo's house. Tell Wuertz to find Dent.
对他们两个人都进行保护性监禁  局长在哪儿
Get them both to Protective custody. Where's the commissioner?
-在市政厅  -封锁大楼
- City hall. - Seal the building.
-在我到达之前不许任何人进出  -明白
- No one in or out till I get there. - Got it.
戈登  你要干什么
Gordon. What are you up to?
我们暂时安全
We're secure.
马上对整栋大楼进行彻底搜查
I want a floor-by-floor search of the entire building.
对不起  先生 我们相信小丑正在威胁你的生命
Sorry sir, we believe the Joker's made a threat against your life.
这些是危险人物  法官
These are dangerous people, judge.
是啊  但你们总得跟我说明下情况吧
Yeah, but you're not giving me a lot of information.
我们也不知道你要去哪儿
Even we don't know where you're going.
拿着信封  上车
Take the envelope, get in,
打开它  它会指示你该去哪儿
open it. It'll tell you where you're headed.
你不能让我一个人面对他们
You can't leave me alone with these people.
整个黑帮都想杀你  你却在担心这些人吗
The whole Mob's after you and you're worried about these guys?
没错  跟他们比  黑帮我根本就不怕
Yeah, compared to this, the Mob doesn't scare me.
戈登  你不太可能自己发现  所以...
Gordon, you're unlikely to discover this for yourself, so...
听我一句  警察局长早被人威胁惯了
...take my word, the police commissioner earns a lot of threats.
很久以前  我就想好了合适的办法应对这种情况
I found the appropriate response to these situations a long time ago.
被人用枪指着让你看事情更清楚
Them gunning for you makes you see things clearly.
是啊  我敢说
Yeah, I bet.
是  它让你想到
Yeah. It makes you think
什么东西是你不能失去的
about things you couldn't stand losing...
想到你想和什么人共度余生
...about who you wanna spend your life with.
-这可是大许诺  -要是黑帮得逞就不是了
- That's a pretty big commitment. - Not if the Mob has their way.
你得去跟我妻子解释
You get to explain to my wife...
为什么我没能赶上晚餐  警长
...why I'm late for dinner, lieutenant.
先生  小丑的扑克牌上有你的DNA
Sir, the joker card had traces of your DNA on it.
-别这样  -好的
- Don't do that. - All right.
-那我们认真点  -好的
- Let's be serious, then. - Okay.
你的答案是什么
What's your answer?
我没有答案
I don't have an answer.
他们怎么得到我的DNA的
How'd they get my DNA?
有人能进入你家或办公室的人
Somebody with access to your office or house...
-一定是从纸巾或者杯子上提取的  -等等
- ...must have lifted a tissue or a glass... - Wait! Wait!
-我猜没有答案就是拒绝  -哈维
- Well, I guess no answer is a no. - Harvey.
-你心里有别人 是吗  -哈维
- It's someone else, isn't it? - Harvey.
别告诉我是韦恩  那家伙完全是个...
Just tell me it's not Wayne. The guy's a complete f...
你在干什么
What are you doing?
去天堂吧
哦  见鬼
Oh, shit.
快叫医生
Get a medic!
他们是冲着他来的
They've come for him.
我们到了
We made it.
藏着别动
Stay hidden.
晚上好  女士们先生们
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen.
今晚由我们给大家助兴
We are tonight's entertainment.
我只有一个问题
I only have one question:
哈维·登特在哪儿
Where is Harvey Dent?
你知道哈维在哪儿吗  你认识他吗
You know where Harvey is? You know who he is?
举起手来  小白脸
Hands up, pretty boy.
知道我能在哪儿找到哈维吗  我得和他谈谈
Do you know where I can find Harvey? I need to talk to him.
一些小事情  不知道啊
Just something little, huh? No.
外面发生什么事了  韦恩
What's going on out there? Wayne!
感谢上帝  你有个避难室
Oh, thank God, you've got a panic room.
等等...
Hey, wait...
你肯定是在开玩笑
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
知道吗  我会为他的挚爱们准备节目的
You know, I'll settle for his loved ones.
我们才不怕你们这些流氓
We're not intimidated by thugs.
知道吗
You know...
你让我想起了我父亲
...you remind me of my father.
我恨我父亲
I hated my father.
行了  住手吧
Okay, stop.
你好啊  美人儿
Well, hello, beautiful.
你一定是哈维的情人了  对吧
You must be Harvey's squeeze. Hm?
长得挺漂亮啊
And you are beautiful.
你很紧张啊  是因为这些伤疤吗
You look nervous. Is it the scars?
你想知道怎么来的吗
You wanna know how I got them?
过来  嘿
Come here. Hey.
看着我
Look at me.
我曾经有过一个妻子  和你一样漂亮
So I had a wife. She was beautiful, like you...
她总说我太过忧郁...
...who tells me I worry too much...
她说我该多笑一笑...
...who tells me I ought to smile more...
她沉迷赌博  欠了很多的债  嘿
...who gambles and gets in deep with the sharks. Hey.
有一天  那些人把她的脸划花了
One day they carve her face.
我们没钱做整容手术  她无法接受自己的模样
And we have no money for surgeries. She can't take it.
我只想再次看见她的笑容罢了
I just wanna see her smile again. Hm?
我想让她知道  我不在乎她脸上的伤疤
I just want her to know that I don't care about the scars.
所以...
So...
我把刀塞进嘴里  然后这样...
...I stick a razor in my mouth and do this...
划开自己的脸
...to myself.
你知道吗  她竟然受不了我的样子
And you know what? She can't stand the sight of me.
她离开了我
She leaves.
现在我看到了有趣的一面
Now I see the funny side.
我现在总是微笑着
Now I'm always smiling.
你的性子挺烈嘛  我喜欢
You got a little fight in you. I like that.
那你也会喜欢我的
Then you're gonna love me.
把枪放下
Drop the gun.
没问题  只要你把面具摘下来
Oh, sure. You just take off your little mask
让我们看看你的真面目  怎样
and show us all who you really are. Hm?
放开她
Let her go.
这选词可真不好
Very poor choice of words.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
别再来一次就好
Let's not do that again.
-哈维还好吗  -他很安全
- Is Harvey okay? - He's safe.
谢谢
Thank you.
杰姆  一切都完了
Jim, it's over.
只要他们找不到刘  他们就拿不到钱
As long as they don't get to Lau, we've cut off their funds.
起诉已经没戏了
The prosecution's over.
现在没人愿意出庭作证
Nobody's standing up in front of a judge...
因为连法官自己和警察局长都被谋杀了
...while judges and police commissioners are getting blown away.
那么登特呢?
What about Dent?
他如果还有点脑子  就已经跑去墨西哥了
He's got any sense, Dent's halfway to Mex...
你把那垃圾关在哪儿了
So where do you keep your trash?
你该出庭了  我需要你活着  至少活到庭审结束
You're due in court. I need you alive long enough to get you on the record.
你们保护不了我  你们连自己都保护不了
You can't protect me. You can't even protect yourselves.
你拒绝合作的话
You refuse to cooperate,
那就别想回到这儿来  直接去监狱
you're not coming back here, you go to County.
你可以计算一下在那里能活多久
How long do you calculate you'll last in there?
攻击我  他们也拿不到钱
Targeting me won't get their money.
我知道黑帮不会轻易罢休
I knew the Mob wouldn't go down easily...
但这次不一样  他们玩过界了
...but this is different. They crossed a line.
是你先过的界
You crossed the line first.
你紧追他们  打击他们  把他们逼得无路可逃
You squeezed them, you hammered them to the point of desperation.
然后在绝望中
And in their desperation,
他们求助于一个自己都不了解的人
they turned to a man they didn't fully understand.
罪犯并不复杂  阿尔弗雷德
Criminals aren't complicated, Alfred.
我们只要找出他们想要的是什么
We just need to figure out what he's after.
恕我直言  韦恩少爷
With respect, Master Wayne...
也许这是一个你也不完全了解的人
...perhaps this is a man you don't fully understand either.
多年前  我在缅甸...
A long time ago, I was in Burma...
和朋友们一起  为当地的政府工作
...and my friends and I were working for the local government.
政府试图收买当地的部落首领
They were trying to buy the loyalty of tribal leaders...
于是用宝石贿赂他们
...by bribing them with precious stones...
但走到仰光北部的森林的时候  货车被强盗抢了
...but their caravans were being raided in a forest north of Rangoon by a bandit.
于是我们就去寻找宝石
So we went looking for the stones.
但过了6个月也没听说任何宝石交易的消息
But in six months, we never met anyone who traded with him.
一天  我看见一个孩子在把玩一颗红宝石...
One day, I saw a child playing with a ruby...
有橘子那么大
...the size of a tangerine.
强盗抢了以后就把宝石扔了
The bandit had been throwing them away.
-那为什么还要抢  -他们觉得打劫有意思
- So why steal them? - Because he thought it was good sport.
因为有些人并不是想要符合常理的东西  比如钱
Because some men aren't looking for anything logical, like money.
他们不接受收买  不怕被威胁
They can't be bought, bullied,
不讲道理  也无法谈判
reasoned or negotiated with.
有些人  他们只想看世界毁灭
Some men just wanna watch the world burn.
你的名字  先生
Your name, sir?
果园路8号  你们会在那找到哈维·登特
Eighth and Orchard. You'll find Harvey Dent there.
看一下名字
Check the names.
"理查·登特"
"Richard Dent."
"帕特里克·哈维"
"Patrick Harvey."
哈维·登特
Harvey Dent.
在你们的人破坏犯罪现场之前  我要10分钟取证
I need 10 minutes with the scene before your men contaminate it.
我们会破坏现场是因为  这些人是因你而死的
Us contaminate it because of you these guys are dead...
警探
Detective!
给我们一点时间  伙计们
Give us a minute, guys.
后面是砖头
That's brick underneath.
-你要搜集弹头做弹道试验吗  -不
- Gonna take ballistics off a shattered bullet? - No.
上面有指纹
Fingerprints.
不论你想做什么  动作要快
Whatever you're gonna do, do it fast.
因为我们知道他的下一个目标了
Because we found his next target.
登在明天的报纸上了
He's put it in tomorrow's paper.
安东尼·加西亚市长 享年40岁
我不知道这声音是不是够大  先生
I'm not sure you made it loud enough, sir.
有什么能为你效劳吗  瑞斯先生
What can I do for you, Mr. Reese?
你之前让我重新评估一次刘氏证券投资的交易
You wanted me to do the diligence on the LSI Holdings deal again.
好吧  我还真发现了一些不对劲的地方
Well, I found some irregularities.
他们的首席执行官都被关起来了
Their CEO is in police custody.
不  不是他们的账目问题  是你们的账目
No, not with their numbers, with yours.
韦恩企业的整个应用科学部门...
Applied Sciences. Whole division of Wayne Enterprises
一夜之间就消失得无影无踪
just disappeared overnight.
我去了档案馆  还翻出了一些旧文件
I went down to the archives and I started pulling some old files.
别告诉我你不认识自己的宝贝
Don't tell me you didn't recognize
晚间新闻上它在把警车都压平了
your baby pancaking cop cars on the evening news.
而现在  你们让整个研发部门在那里大把地烧钱
Now you got the entire R & D Department burning through cash...
声称是在为军方研发军用式移动电话?
...claiming it's related to cell phones for the Army?
你现在又在给他制造什么  火箭飞船吗
What are you building for him now, a rocket ship?
我要...
I want...
从今以后  每年1千万汇入我的账户
...$10 million a year for the rest of my life.
我就有话直说了
Let me get this straight.
你觉得你的客户
You think that your client...
全世界最富有的  最有权力的人之一
One of the wealthiest, most powerful men in the world,
私底下是个义警
is secretly a vigilante...
他每晚赤手空拳把罪犯打成肉酱
...who spends his nights beating criminals to a pulp with his bare hands...
而你的计划是  打算敲诈他?
...and your plan is to blackmail this person?
祝你好运
Good luck.
那...
When...
把这个收好吧
Keep that.
这是原始扫描
This is your original scan.
这是重建之后的
Here it is reengineered.
这就是他装子弹的时候留下的指纹
And there's the thumbprint he left when he pushed the round in the clip.
我给你拷贝一份
I'll get you a copy.
韦恩先生  你重组了研发部门吗
Mr. Wayne, did you reassign R & D?
是的  为一个政府的通讯项目
Yeah. Government telecommunications project.
我怎么不知道和政府有合约?
Wasn't aware we had any government contracts.
你知道  卢修斯  我喜欢给人惊喜
You know, Lucius, I'm playing this one pretty close to the chest.
那好吧
Fair enough.
蝙蝠侠始终没有现身  即使是在悼念博特局长时
With no word from the Batman, even as they mourn Commissioner Loeb...
这些警察也在担心小丑会不会让他在
...these cops have to wonder if the Joker will make good on his threat...
哥谭时报讣告栏上要杀死市长的威胁成为现实
...in the obituary column of The Gotham Times to kill the mayor.
我查遍了所有数据库  有四种可能性
I've checked all the databases. There are four possibles.
交叉对照这些地址
Cross-reference the addresses.
找找周边酒店 能俯瞰游行队伍的位置
Look for Parkside, overlooking the parade.
我找到一个
I got one.
马文·怀特  住在兰道夫公寓1502号
Melvin White, 1502 Randolph Apartments.
犯过故意伤害罪 两次进过阿卡姆精神病院
Aggravated assault, moved to Arkham twice.
屋顶有什么发现吗
What do you got on the roof?
在严密监控  但说实话  窗户实在太多了
We're tight, but frankly, there's a lot of windows up here.
劳博局长终其一生致力于秉公执法
Commissioner Loeb dedicated his life to law enforcement...
还有维持社会的和谐稳定
...and to the protection of his community.
还记得  当我刚上任的时候
I remember when I first took office...
问他  想不想继续担任警察局长
...and I asked if he wanted to stay on as commissioner.
他说可以
And he said he would,
只要我不把政治带入他的办公室就行
provided I kept my politics out of his office.
很明显  他不是个装腔作势的人
Clearly he was not a man who minced words,
他也没必要
nor should he have been.
他任警察局长期间
A number of policies that
推行的很多政策都不受欢迎
he enacted as commissioner were unpopular.
投诉这些政策的电话和信函  不断涌进我的办公室
Policies that flooded my office with angry calls and letters...
-你是谁  -怎么回事
- Who's that? - What happened?
他们抢走了我们的枪
They took our guns.
还有我们的制服
And our uniforms.
我们认可这个人的牺牲奉献
And as we recognize the sacrifice of this man...
我们必须铭记  保持警惕才能带来安定
...we must remember that vigilance is the price of safety.
仪仗队  预备
Stand by. Honor guard.
立正  举枪
Attention. Port arms.
预备  瞄准  发射
Ready! Aim! Fire!
预备  瞄准
Ready! Aim!
趴下  别动
Stay down! Don't move!
市长先生  快带他离开
Mr. Mayor. Get him out of here.
-等会再见  -你为什么回去
- I'll see you later. - Why are you going back?
给我出去
Get out of here.
关于小丑你知道什么
Tell me what you know about the Joker.
瑞秋·道斯
不
No.
我很抱歉  芭芭拉
I'm sorry, Barbara.
杰米  去和你妹妹玩  去吧  宝贝
Jimmy, go play with your sister. Go ahead, honey.
有什么我们能做的  请尽管吩咐
If there's anything we can do, anything you need,
我们是来帮你的
we're here for you.
你当时在吗
Are you out there?
你在吗  是你害我们这样  是你
Are you? You brought this craziness on us. You did!
是你把我们害成这样的
You brought this on us!
关了吧  他不会来的  他不想见我们
Switch it off, he ain't coming. He doesn't wanna talk to us.
老天保佑他想见的人吧
God help whoever he does wanna talk to.
不能去安静一点的地方吗  这里我们没法说话
Can't we go someplace quieter? We can't hear each other talk.
你凭什么觉得我想跟你说话
What makes you think I wanna hear you talk?
什么
What?
-怎么了  -先接电话
- Yeah? - Second.
好的
Okay.
-哈维  你在哪里  -你在哪里
- Harvey, where are you? - Where are you?
我在你应该待的地方  重案组
I'm where you should be, at Major Crimes.
乱得我都忙不过来了
I'm trying to deal with all of this mess.
能把指纹分析结果给我吗
Can I get the fingerprint analysis?
瑞秋  听着  你在那里不安全
Rachel, listen. You're not safe there.
-这是戈登的单位  -戈登已经死了
- This is Gordon's unit. - Gordon's gone.
-他对这些人打了包票的  -结果他死了
- He vouched for these men. - And he's gone.
小丑下一个目标就是你
The Joker's named you next.
天哪  这城市里就没一个能信任的人了吗
God, is there someone, is there anyone in this town we can trust?
布鲁斯
Bruce.
我们可以相信布鲁斯·韦恩
We can trust Bruce Wayne.
不  瑞秋  我知道他是你的朋友  可是...
No. Rachel, I know you're his friend, but...
哈维  相信我
Harvey, trust me.
布鲁斯的公寓是目前全城最安全的地方
Bruce's penthouse is now the safest place in the city.
那你现在直接去那里
Then you go straight there.
别告诉任何人  我会去那里找你的
Don't tell anybody and I'll find you there.
我爱你
I love you.
我要找小丑
I want the Joker.
大家都是专业人士...
From one professional to another...
你如果打算吓唬人的话  找个好点的位置吧
...you're trying to scare somebody, pick a better spot.
这样的高度  掉下去也死不了
From this height, the fall wouldn't kill me.
正合我意
I'm counting on it.
-他在哪里  -我不知道他在哪儿  都是他主动找我们
- Where is he? - I don't know where he is. He found us.
他肯定有朋友知道
He must have friends.
朋友?  你见过那家伙没有?
Friends? Have you met this guy?
总有人知道他在哪儿
Someone knows where he is.
没有人会告诉你的
Nobody's gonna tell you nothing.
他们早把你看透了
They're wise to your act.
你有准则  小丑是没有准则的
You got rules. The Joker, he's got no rules.
没有人会为了你出卖小丑
Nobody's gonna cross him for you.
你想找他  只有一个办法
If you want this guy, you got one way.
你已经知道是什么办法了
But you already know what that is.
只要摘下面具  他就会来找你
Just take off that mask, let him come find you.
或者  你可以让更多人为你的
Or you can let a couple more people get killed
优柔寡断而送命
while you make up your mind.
你想玩游戏  是吗
You wanna play games?
感觉怎么样
How's that feel?
-你不会杀人的  -我不会
- You wouldn't. - I wouldn't!
你认为我不会杀人?
- You don't think I will? - Mm-mm.
你以为我不会杀人?
对  对  我不杀人
No. No, I wouldn't.
所以我不会让自己决定
That's why I'm not gonna leave it up to me.
正面  你能留着小命
Heads, you get to keep your head.
背面...
Tails...
就没那么幸运了
...not so lucky.
要告诉我小丑的事情吗
So you wanna tell me about the Joker?
-再来一次  -我什么也不知道  天呐  别来了
- Let's go again. - I don't know anything! God, don't!
这游戏不是你说了算  朋友
You're not playing the odds, friend.
再来一次吧
Let's do it again.
你要拿一条人命来赌吗
You'd leave a man's life to chance?
-不完全是  -他叫托马斯·希夫
- Not exactly. - His name's Schiff, Thomas.
他是偏执精神分裂症患者  精神病院出来的
He's a paranoid schizophrenic, former patient at Arkham.
小丑专挑这种类型
The kind of mind the Joker attracts.
你能指望他说些什么
What do you expect to learn from him?
小丑杀了戈登  下一个目标就是瑞秋
The Joker killed Gordon. He's gonna kill Rachel.
你是希望的象征  这点是我做不到的
You're the symbol of hope I could never be.
你坚决打击犯罪团伙
Your stand against organized crime...
你是这些年来哥谭市首次出现的正义之光
...is the first legitimate ray of light in Gotham in decades.
要是有人看见这场面的话  一切都完了
If anyone saw this, everything would be undone.
你从街上逮捕的所有罪犯都会被释放
All the criminals you pulled off the streets would be released...
杰姆·戈登的死就一文不值了
...and Jim Gordon will have died for nothing.
明天你要召开一个新闻发布会
You're gonna hold a press conference tomorrow.
-为什么  -不能有人再因我而死了
- Why? - No one else will die because of me.
哥谭的未来就交给你了
Gotham's in your hands now.
不行
You can't.
你不能屈服
You can't give in.
You can't give in!
哈维打电话来
Harvey called.
他说蝙蝠侠要去自首了
He said Batman's gonna turn himself in.
我没有选择
I have no choice.
你真的认为这样
You honestly think that's
能阻止小丑继续杀人吗
gonna keep the Joker from killing people?
也许不行  但我的双手已经染够了鲜血
Maybe not. But I have enough blood on my hands.
现在我明白了
And I've seen now
用什么办法才能阻止像他那样的罪犯
what I would have to become to stop men like him.
你说过  如果有一天  我的使命完成了
You once told me that if the day came when I was finished...
我们就能在一起
...that we'd be together.
布鲁斯  别把我当成你回归普通生活的希望
Bruce, don't make me your one hope for a normal life.
你当时是认真的吗
Did you mean it?
当然
Yes.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
如果你自首的话  他们是不会让我们在一起的
If you turn yourself in, they're not gonna let us be together.
-日志也要烧掉吗  -全部销毁
- Logs as well? - Everything.
所有牵涉到卢修斯或者瑞秋的都不能留下
Anything that could lead back to Lucius or Rachel.
不断有人死去  阿尔弗雷德  我该怎么做?
People are dying, Alfred. What would you have me do?
忍耐  韦恩少爷  坚持住
Endure, Master Wayne. Take it.
他们会因此而恨你  但那才是蝙蝠侠的意义
They'll hate you for it, but that's the point of Batman.
他可以被排斥
He can be the outcast.
他可以做出别人做不出的选择
He can make the choice that no one else can make.
正确的选择
The right choice.
不  今天  我发现蝙蝠侠也有做不到事情
No, today I found out what Batman can't do.
他不能忍受这些
He can't endure this.
今天你可以说"我告诉过你"
Today you get to say "I told you so."
今天  我不想说这句话
Today, I don't want to.
但我的确早跟你说了
But I did bloody tell you.
他们大概会把我一并抓起来
I suppose they're gonna lock me up as well...
当成你的共犯
...as your accomplice.
共犯?  我会告诉他们这都是你主使的
Accomplice? I'm gonna tell them the whole thing was your idea.
女士们先生们  感谢你们的到来
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for coming.
我召开此次媒体发布会有两个原因
I've called this press conference for two reasons.
第一  向哥谭的市民保证
Firstly, to assure the citizens of Gotham...
我们已采取一切可能的措施  防范小丑的杀人举动
...that everything that can be done over the Joker killings is being done.
第二  是因为蝙蝠侠已经决定要投案自首
Secondly, because the Batman has offered to turn himself in.
但首先  让我们考虑一下状况
But let's consider the situation.
我们是否应屈服于这个恐怖分子的要求
Should we give in to this terrorist's demands?
我们是否真的认为他会...
Do we really think he's gonna...?
你情愿保护一个无视法律的义警
You'd rather protect an outlaw vigilante
也不愿保护哥谭市民吗
than the lives of citizens?
蝙蝠侠是非法没错
The Batman is an outlaw.
但这并不是我们让他自首的原因...
That's not why we demand he turn himself in,
我们这么做是因为恐惧
we're doing it because we're scared.
一直以来  我们都感激蝙蝠侠惩奸除恶
We've been happy to let Batman clean up our streets till now.
现在的情况比以前更糟糕
Things are worse than ever!
是的  没错
Yes, they are.
但黎明前是最黑暗的时刻
But the night is darkest just before the dawn.
我向你们承诺
And I promise you...
黎明即将到来
...the dawn is coming.
终有一天  蝙蝠侠要给
One day, the Batman will have
他所践踏的法律一个交代  给我们一个交代
to answer for the laws he's broken. But to us...
而不是给这个疯子
...not to this madman.
-不能再死警察了  -没错
- No more dead cops! - Yeah!
他应该投案自首
He should turn himself in!
-交出蝙蝠侠  快点  -他在哪里
- Give us the Batman! Come on! - Where is he?
那好吧  拘捕蝙蝠侠
So be it. Take the Batman into custody.
-什么  -他在这里?
- What? - Is he here?
我就是蝙蝠侠
I am the Batman.
-什么  -不会吧
-What? - Come on.
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred.
他为什么让哈维这么做
Why is he letting Harvey do this?
他去新闻发布会现场了
He went down to the press conference.
我知道  可他只是袖手旁观
I know. He just stood by.
也许布鲁斯和登特先生...
Perhaps both Bruce and Mr. Dent...
认为蝙蝠侠的存在是为了一些更重要的事情
...believe that Batman stands for something more important...
而不应屈服于恐怖分子的戏言
...than the whims of a terrorist, Miss Dawes...
即使所有人都因此恨他
...even if everyone hates him for it.
这就是他做出的牺牲
That's the sacrifice he's making.
他不会成为英雄  但他比英雄更重要
He's not being a hero. He's being something more.
是啊  你说得没错
Yeah, you're absolutely right.
让哈维替他承受这些的确不是英雄之举
Letting Harvey take the fall for this is not heroic at all.
你比任何人都更了解他
You know him better than anyone.
确实如此
I do.
等到时机成熟的时候  能请你把这个转交给他吗
Will you give this to him for me? When the time is right?
我怎么知道是什么时候
How will I know?
信没封口
It's not sealed.
再见  阿尔弗雷德
Goodbye, Alfred.
再见  瑞秋
Bye, Rachel.
抱歉  我没来得及跟你解释
Sorry I didn't have time to talk this through.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
他们要把我转移到中央拘留所
They're transferring me to Central Holding.
这是小丑的好机会  要是他发动袭击
This is the Joker's chance, and when he attacks,
蝙蝠侠就会把他拿下
the Batman will take him down.
听我说  这太危险了
Listen to me. This is too dangerous.
我们把他送到监狱以后  就完成任务了
We get this guy to County, he's their problem.
沿路的障碍都会被清除
The streets will be cleared along your route...
行动吧  车队无论如何都不能停下
...so let's go. The convoys stop for no reason.
希望你车技靠谱  伙计
I hope you got some moves, pal.
他在拿你当诱饵
He's using you as bait.
他也不知道自己能不能抓住小丑
He doesn't know if he can get the Joker.
迄今为止他都没成功
He's failed so far.
你怎么知道他在想什么
How do you know what he's thinking?
我就是知道  这不是你一个人的事情
I just do. Anyway, this isn't just about you.
那些依赖你的人们又该怎么办
What about the people depending on you
他们指望你用正义净化城市...
to clean the city up and do it honorably and...?
哈维  告诉大家真相吧
Harvey. Tell everyone the truth.
正面  我会没事的
Heads, I go through with it.
这是你的生命啊
This is your life.
你不能拿自己的命赌运气
You can't leave something like that to chance.
我没有
I'm not.
你自己创造运气
You make your own luck.
嘿  你得和其他人一样等着  伙计
Hey, you wait like everybody else, pal.
这是什么情况
What the hell is that?
前方有障碍  前方有障碍
Obstruction ahead, obstruction ahead!
该死  各单位注意
Damn it! All units divert
走地下第五隧道  重复  走地下
down onto Lower Fifth. I repeat, exit down.
走地下
Exit down!
第五隧道?  我们会变成砧上鱼肉的
Lower Fifth? We'll be like turkeys on Thanksgiving.
老天  拜托  快离开这儿  快走
Jesus. Come on, get us out of here. Let's go.
听着  我们需要增援  我们被人跟上了
Listen, we need backup. We've got company.
我们有麻烦了  伙计们
We got trouble, guys.
子弹上膛
Lock and load!
见鬼  那是什么
The hell was that?
-这些都是防弹的吧  -他需要
- These are built for that, right? - He'll need something...
更强的火力才能打穿
...A lot bigger to get through this.
那是什么
What is that?
那是什么  火箭炮吗
What is that, a bazooka?
我可不是来干这个的
I didn't sign up for this!
小心
Look out.
Look out!
快点  快点走
Come on, let's go!
哈维  哈维  哈维·登特
Harvey, Harvey, Harvey Dent.
哦  请让一下  我想开车
Oh, excuse me. I wanna drive.
扫描所有系统  扫描所有系统
Scanning all systems. Scanning all systems.
我们得到地面去  我们急需空中支援  赶快
We gotta get topside. We need air support, now!
我喜欢这活儿  我喜欢
I like this job. I like it.
灾难级损坏  弹出程序启动
Damage catastrophic. Eject sequence initiated.
再见
Goodbye.
自毁
我们已经到达  准备让他们尝尝我们的厉害
We're on point, ready to give them some of their own medicine.
这才像样  空中掩护
That's what I'm talking about. Air cav.
好了  干掉他们
Okay, rack them up.
干掉他们  干掉他们  干掉他们
Rack them up, rack them up, rack them up.
这可不妙
That's not good.
这可一点都不妙
Okay, that's not good!
现在  蝙蝠侠出场了
Now, there's a Batman.
噢  你想玩玩吗  放马过来
Ooh, you wanna play. Come on.
来啊
Come on.
他没撞着
He missed!
你不能停在这  我们成了活靶了
You can't stop here. We're like sitting ducks!
来吧  来吧
Come on, come on.
来吧  来吧  快来撞我  快来撞我  来吧
Come on. Come on. I want you to do it, I want you to do it, come on.
来吧
Come on.
来吧  来吧  快来撞我
Come on. Come on. I want you to do it,
快来撞我  来吧  撞我
I want you to do it. Come on, hit me.
撞我  撞我  来吧  撞我
hit me, hit me. Come on, hit me!
撞我
Hit me!
来吧  来吧  啊啊啊
Come on, come on. Aah!
你能稍微等我一会儿吗
Could you please just give me a minute?
我们逮住你了  你个狗娘养的
We got you, you son of a bitch.
戈登  你还真喜欢给人惊喜呀
Gor... You do like to play things pretty close to the chest.
我们抓住他了  哈维
We got him, Harvey.
登特先生
Mr. Dent!
作为哥谭的大英雄  你有何感想
How does it feel to be the biggest hero in Gotham?
不  我不是英雄
No, I'm no hero.
哥谭出色的警察  他们才是英雄
Gotham's finest, they're the heroes.
但是你和你的同事们
But you and your office
一直以来都在和蝙蝠侠保持合作
have been working with the Batman all along.
没有  但我相信他做的是正确的事
No, but I trusted him to do the right thing.
你指的是...
Which was?
他救了我的命
Saving my ass.
好了  提问到此结束  请让他过去  让他过去
All right, people, that's enough. Let him be. Let him be.
谢谢你  警探
Thank you, detective.
我还得去赴我那美丽不安的女友的约会
I've got a date with a pretty upset girlfriend.
-我懂  长官  -登特先生...
- I figured, counselor. - Mr. Dent, sir...
-能接受我的头版新闻一个提问吗  -登特先生
- ...how about one for the front page, sir? - Mr. Dent.
站远一点  所有人
Stand away! All of you!
我可不想被他的黑帮律师抓住任何把柄  你们懂吗
I don't want anything for his Mob lawyer to use, you understand?
死而复生了
Back from the dead.
我...
I, uh...
不能拿家人的安全冒险啊
...couldn't risk my family's safety.
我们对他了解多少
What do we got?
什么都不知道  没有相应的指纹  DNA  牙科记录
Nothing. No matches on prints, DNA, dental.
衣服是定制的  没有标签
Clothing is custom, no labels.
口袋里什么也没有  除了刀就是纱布
Nothing in his pockets but knives and lint.
不知道名字
No name.
-也没有其他化名  -快回家吧  戈登
- No other alias. - Go home, Gordon.
小丑会一直关到早上  去好好休息一下
The clown'll keep till morning. Go get some rest.
你需要休息
You're gonna need it.
明天你有更艰巨的工作
Tomorrow you take the big job.
这一点可由不得你作主  戈登局长
You don't have any say in the matter. Commissioner Gordon.
对不起  我不能拿你们的安全冒险
I'm sorry, I couldn't risk your safety.
瞧瞧这些丑八怪
Look at these ugly bastards.
-我不舒服  -你杀了警察
- I don't feel good. - You're a cop killer.
你应该庆幸你的头还没被砍下来
You're lucky to be feeling anything below the neck.
-求你了  -离围栏远点儿
- Please! - Step away from the bars!
我肚子不舒服
My insides hurt.
是蝙蝠侠救了你吗  爸爸
Did Batman save you, Daddy?
实际上  这次
Actually, this time...
是我救了他
...I saved him.
他交代什么了吗
Has he said anything yet?
晚上好啊  局长
Evening, commissioner.
哈维·登特没有回到家
Harvey Dent never made it home.
-当然没有  -你对他做了什么
- Of course not. - What have you done with him?
我?
Me?
我一直在这儿啊
I was right here.
你让谁送他回去的?
Who did you leave him with?
你的手下吗?
Hm? Your people?
当然了  假设他们还算是你的手下
Assuming, of course, that they are still your people...
而不是马若尼的
...and not Maroni's.
是不是很沮丧  局长
Does it depress you, commissioner...
知道自己其实有多孤单了吧
...to know just how alone you really are?
你是不是觉得
Does it make you feel
对于哈维·登特的处境  你要负很大责任
responsible for Harvey Dent's current predicament?
-他在哪儿  -现在几点了
- Where is he? - What's the time?
这和几点有什么关系
What difference does that make?
根据时间  他可能在一个地方  或者好几个地方
Well, depending on the time, he may be in one spot or several.
如果你要玩游戏
If we're gonna play games...
我得先来杯咖啡
...I'm gonna need a cup of coffee.
是"好警察坏警察"游戏吗
Ah, the "Good cop, bad cop" Routine?
不完全是
Not exactly.
不要上来就打头
Never start with the head.
这会让受害者头晕   然后就感觉不到...
The victim gets all fuzzy. He can't feel the next...
瞧见没
See?
你想要找我  我来了
You wanted me. Here I am.
我想看看你会怎么做
I wanted to see what you'd do.
你果然没有让我失望
And you didn't disappoint.
你让五个人因你而死
You let five people die.
还让登特替你背黑锅
Then you let Dent take your place.
连我这样的人  都觉得冷血
Even to a guy like me, that's cold.
登特在哪儿
Where's Dent?
那些黑帮笨蛋想除掉你
Those Mob fools want you gone
这样他们就又能为所欲为了
so they can get back to the way things were.
但是我知道真相
But I know the truth.
已经回不去了  你改变了一切
There's no going back. You've changed things.
-永远的  -那你为什么还要杀我
- Forever. - Then why do you wanna kill me?
我才不想杀你
I don't wanna kill you.
没有你我还能干什么
What would I do without you?
再回去敲诈那些黑帮贩子?  不  不
Go back to ripping off Mob dealers? No, no.
不  不  你
No. No, you...
你让我变得完整
You complete me.
你就是个为了钱杀人的垃圾
You're garbage who kills for money.
别像他们那样肤浅  你不像他们
Don't talk like one of them. You're not.
即使你想变成他们中的一员
Even if you'd like to be.
对他们来说  你只是一个怪物
To them, you're just a freak...
像我一样
...like me.
他们现在需要你
They need you right now...
等他们用完你了
...but when they don't...
就会把你踢走 像驱逐麻风病人一样
...they'll cast you out like a leper.
你也看见了  他们的道德  他们的准则
You see, their morals, their code...
只是个糟糕的笑话
...it's a bad joke.
一碰上麻烦就什么都忘了
Dropped at the first sign of trouble.
他们只在太平盛世时才会充当好人
They're only as good as  the world allows them to be.
我会让你看到的
I'll show you.
当一切分崩离析的时候  这些
When the chips are down, these...
这些文明人
These civilized people...
他们就会互相残杀
...they'll eat each other.
瞧  我可不是怪物
See, I'm not a monster.
我只是走在别人前面罢了
I'm just ahead of the curve.
登特在哪儿
Where's Dent?
你一直遵循准则  还认为这样能拯救你
You have all these rules, and you think they'll save you.
-他能控制自己  -我只有一条准则
- He's in control. - I have one rule.
看来你得打破这条准则  才能知道真相了
Oh. Then that's the rule you'll have to break to know the truth.
真相是
Which is?
要想生存  最好的方式是没有准则
The only sensible way to live is without rules.
今晚  你将会打破你唯一的准则
And tonight you're gonna break your one rule.
我是在考虑
I'm considering it.
不  只剩一分钟了  所以你得按我的规矩来
There's only minutes left, so you'll have to play my game...
如果你想救出他们中的一个
...if you wanna save one of them.
"他们"?
"Them"?
知道吗  有那么一会儿  我真的以为你就是登特
You know, for a while there, I thought you really were Dent.
你奋不顾身的跳出窗户去救她
The way you threw yourself after her.
瞧瞧你自己
Look at you go.
哈维知道你和他的小女友有一腿吗
Does Harvey know about you and his little bunny?
他们到底在哪儿
Where are they?!
杀人就是一种选择
Killing is making a choice.
-他们在哪儿  -两条命  你只能选一条
- Where are they?! - Choose between one life or the other.
是你的地方检察官朋友  还是他娇羞的准新娘
Your friend the district attorney, or his blushing bride-to-be.
你威胁不了我  你没有威胁我的筹码
You have nothing, nothing to threaten me with.
使再大的劲都没用
Nothing to do with all your strength.
别担心  我会告诉你他们在哪儿  都告诉你
Don't worry, I'm gonna tell you where they are, both of them.
接下来才是重点  你得做出选择
And that's the point. You'll have to choose.
他在52街250号
He's at 250 52nd Street...
而她在西塞罗的第十大街
...and she's on Avenue X at Cicero.
-你去救哪个  -瑞秋
- Which one you going after? - Rachel.
我们去救登特
We're getting Dent!
52街250号
250 52nd Street!
有人吗
Hello?
有人能听到我吗
Can anybody hear me?
有人吗
Hello!
-瑞秋?  -哈维?
- Rachel? - Harvey.
哈维  谢天谢地  你没事吧
Oh, Harvey, thank God. Are you okay?
我没事  我在一个...
I'm all right. I'm in a...
我在一个仓库里面
I'm in a warehouse.
我被他们用绳捆住了  旁边都是油桶
They got me wired to these oil drums.
我也是
I am too.
哈维
Harvey.
我要打电话
I want my phone call.
我想要  我想要  我要打电话
I want it. I want it. I want my phone call.
想得美
That's nice.
我杀了多少你的朋友?
How many of your friends have I killed?
我干了二十年警察
I'm a 20-year man...
我能分清哪种是需要学点礼仪常识的混混
...and I know the difference between punks who need a lesson in manners...
哪种是你这样把被揍当享受的怪胎
...and the freaks like you who would just enjoy it.
你杀了我六个朋友
And you killed six of my friends.
六个
Six?
求你了  我肚子不舒服
Please. My insides hurt.
我可不关心  退后
I don't really care. Back away.
头儿说了他会让这些声音都消失
The boss said he'd make the voices go away.
他说他会来的  会把它们变成明亮的灯光
He said he'd go inside and replace them with bright lights...
就像圣诞节
...like Christmas.
你疯了  伙计  退后
You're out of your mind, pal. Back off.
叫医生到牢房来  快点  把门打开
Medic to the holding tank. Come on. Get the door open.
你们几个  退后
You guys, back off!
听着  我们余下的时间不多了
Listen, we don't have a lot of time.
他们告诉我  我们只有一人能活下去
They told me that only one of us was gonna make it...
他们会让我们的朋友来选择
...and that they were gonna let our friends choose.
好吧  瑞秋
Okay, Rachel.
会没事的  一切都会好的
It's gonna be fine. It's gonna be all right.
他们会来救你的
They're coming for you.
听我说  我会帮你
Listen to me. I'll help you.
只要告诉我  告诉我你那里的情况
Just talk me through what's going on with you.
-你能找到锋利点的家伙吗  -我正在努力
- Can you find something, anything, sharp? - I'm trying.
-怎么回事  -妈的
- What's...? - Shit.
哈维?
Harvey?
哈维  发生什么事了
Harvey, what's happening?
所有在岗警员到250-52号大街集合
All available units, converge at 250 52nd Street.
你想知道我为什么要用刀吗
Do you wanna know why I use a knife?
枪杀人太快了
Guns are too quick.
你品尝不到所有的
You can't savor all the...
细腻感受
...little emotions.
要知道  死亡前的那一刻
You see, in their last moments...
人们才会暴露出自己的本性
...people show you who they really are.
所以某种程度上  我比你更了解你的那些朋友
So in a way, I knew your friends better than you ever did.
你想知道他们当中谁是胆小鬼吗
Would you like to know which of them were cowards?
-这是什么  -天哪
- What's that? - Jeez.
他好像有某种
He's got some kind of a...
-伤口  -我知道你会很享受这个
- ...contusion. - I know you're gonna enjoy this.
我会试着从中得到更多享受
I'm gonna have to try and enjoy it even more.
把武器放下
Just put it down.
别紧张  别紧张  赶紧放下武器
Take it easy. Take it easy. Drop the weapon now!
都是我的错
It's my own damn fault,
-只管开枪  -放他走  快放下武器
- just shoot him! - Let him go now! Drop it!
-什么  抱歉  -你想怎么样
- What? Sorry? - What do you want?
我只想要打个电话
I just want my phone call.
怎么了  怎么了  发生了什么
What...? What...? What's happening?
快回答我  哪怕只说一句话
Just talk to me, just for one second.
-行吗  -好吧
- All right? - Right.
那是  手机吗
Is that a phone?
注意看路
Mount the curb!
哈维  为了以防万一  我想告诉你一件事  好吗
Harvey, just in case, I wanna tell you something, okay?
别那么想  瑞秋  他们就要来了
Don't think like that, Rachel. They're coming.
我知道他们快来了  但是我不想他们来
I know they are, but I don't want them to.
我的生活不能没有你  我已经想好了给你的回答
I don't wanna live without you, and I do have an answer for you.
我的答案是我愿意
My answer is yes.
不  不  不
No! No! No!
不要救我  你为什么要来救我
Not me! Why are you coming for me?
不
No!
瑞秋  瑞秋
Rachel! Rachel!
-哈维  -不  不  瑞秋
- Harvey. - No! No! Rachel!
好吧
Okay.
瑞秋
Rachel!
不  不
No! No!
哈维  没事了  好了  听着
Harvey, it's okay. It's all right. Listen.
尽管...
Somewh...
不  局长
No, commissioner!
瑞秋  不
Rachel! No!
你好啊
Hello there.
重案组出事了  小丑逃走了
Back at the MCU, the Joker's gone.
也救走了刘?
With Lau?
小丑是故意被抓的
The Joker planned to be caught.
他早料到了我会把他关在重案组
He wanted me to lock him up in the MCU.
亲爱的布鲁斯
Dear Bruce:
我必须诚实而明确的告诉你
I need to be honest and clear.
我准备嫁给哈维·登特了
I'm going to marry Harvey Dent.
我深爱着他  并且愿意与他共度余生
I love him, and I wanna spend the rest of my life with him.
我对你说过如果哥谭市不再需要蝙蝠侠
When I told you that if Gotham no longer needed Batman,
我们就能在一起
we could be together...
我是认真的
...I meant it.
但现在我明白了  你不当蝙蝠侠的那天永远不会到来
But now I'm sure the day won't come when you no longer need Batman.
我希望会有那么一天
I hope it does.
如果那一天真的到来  我会在你身边
And if it does, I will be there...
但只是作为你的朋友
...but as your friend.
对不起  哈维
I'm sorry, Harvey.
对不起  我让你失望了
I'm sorry to let you down.
如果你对我失去信心  请不要对民众失去信心
If you lose your faith in me, please keep your faith in people.
永远爱你的  瑞秋
Love, now and always, Rachel.
准备了一点早餐
Prepared a little breakfast.
-那好吧  -阿尔弗雷德
- Very well, then. - Alfred.
是的  韦恩少爷
Yes, Master Wayne?
是我害死她的吗
Did I bring this on her?
我本来是想激发善举
I was meant to inspire good...
而不是疯狂  不是死亡
...not madness, not death.
你已经激发善举了
You have inspired good.
你给了哥谭的罪犯狠狠一耳光
But you spat in the faces of Gotham's criminals.
你没料到有牺牲是在所难免的吗
Didn't you think there might be casualties?
黎明之前总会更黑暗
Things always get worse before they get better.
但是瑞秋  阿尔弗雷德
But Rachel, Alfred.
瑞秋  坚信你捍卫的一切
Rachel believed in what you stood for...
我们捍卫的一切
...what we stand for.
哥谭市需要你
Gotham needs you.
不  哥谭需要它真正的英雄
No, Gotham needs its true hero...
我却让那个杀人恶魔  把他炸了个半死
...and I let that murdering psychopath blow him half to hell.
所以既然如此  现在
Which is why, for now...
人们只能依靠你了
...they're gonna have to make do with you.
她本来要等我的  阿尔弗雷德
She was gonna wait for me, Alfred.
登特还不知道
Dent doesn't know.
他永远也不会知道了
He can never know.
这是什么
What's that?
-现在不急  -那个强盗...
- It can wait. - That bandit...
躲在缅甸森林里的那个
...in the forest in Burma.
-你们抓住他了没  -抓住了
- Did you catch him? - Yes.
怎么抓住的
How?
我们放火烧了整个森林
We burned the forest down.
他是一个从事并购咨询的顶尖律师  掌握了可靠信息
He's credible source, an M & A lawyer from a leading consultancy.
揭秘 蝙蝠侠的真实身份
他说他自己之前一直在
He says he's waited as long as he can
等待蝙蝠侠作出正确的决定
for Batman to do the right thing.
现在他决定自己来做这件事
Now he's taking matters into his own hands.
五点整本台将现场直播  揭晓蝙蝠侠的真实身份
We'll be live at 5 with the true identity of the Batman.
瑞秋的事我很抱歉
I'm sorry about Rachel.
医生说你正忍受着剧烈疼痛
The doctor says you're in agonizing pain,
但是却不肯接受药物治疗
but that you won't accept medication.
说你还拒绝...
That you're refusing to...
接受皮肤移植
...accept skin grafts.
记得那个名字吗
Remember that name...
你们给我起的
...you all had for me...
当我还在内务部的时候
...when I was at Internal Affairs?
是什么  戈登
What was it, Gordon?
哈维  我...
Harvey, I...
说出来
Say it.
说啊
Say it!
双面人  双面人哈维
Two-Face. Harvey Two-Face.
我何必隐藏自己呢?
Why should I hide who I am?
我知道你提醒过我
I know you tried to warn me.
对不起
I'm sorry.
是乌尔茨把你接走的  他是他们的人吗
Wuertz picked you up. Was he working for them?
你知道是谁接走了瑞秋吗
Do you know who picked up Rachel?
哈维  我必须知道我还能信任手下哪些人
Harvey, I need to know which of my men I can trust.
为什么现在你肯听我的了
Why would you listen to me now?
对不起  哈维
I'm sorry, Harvey.
不
No.
不  你不用道歉
No, you're not.
现在还不用
Not yet.
这些疯狂的事  有点过分了
This craziness, it's too much.
你在请小丑出来之前  就应该想到的
Should've thought about that before you let the clown out of the box.
你想抓他吗
You want him?
我可以告诉你今天下午他会在哪儿
I can tell you where he'll be this afternoon.
你做事倒是没那么疯癫嘛
Not so crazy as you look.
我说过  我这人言出必行
I told you, I'm a man of my word.
那个意大利佬在哪儿
Where is the Italian?
所有作战部队  20分钟内到目标地点集合
All tactical units will converge on the location in 20 minutes.
后备部队守住所有可能的逃生通道
I want auxiliary units to cover all possible getaway routes.
拜托
Please.
小丑兄  你那份钱准备怎么花
Joker-man, what you do with all your money?
知道吗 我这个人口味不重
You see, I'm a guy of simple taste.
我喜欢
I enjoy...
炸药
...dynamite...
还有火药
...and gunpowder...
以及汽油
...and gasoline.
这到底...
What the...?
你知道它们之间有什么共同点吗
And you know the thing that they have in common?
都很便宜
They're cheap.
我想知道  他们付多少钱来让你揭穿蝙蝠侠的身份
I wanna know how much are they paying you to say who Batman is?
我们的机会来了  刘要抓活的  小丑死活都行
This is our chance. I want Lau alive. The Joker, either way.
嘿  杰姆  来看看这个
Hey, Jim. Get a load of this.
接通下一个电话
Let's take the next caller.
哈维·登特都不想向那个疯子屈服
Harvey Dent didn't wanna give in to this maniac.
你觉得你比他更明白状况吗
You think you know better?
我想如果我们现在再和登特谈谈
I think that if we could talk to Dent today,
他可能就不那么想了
he may feel differently.
当然  我们希望他早日康复
And we wish him a speedy recovery.
因为老天知道我们多么需要他
Because God knows, we need him now.
你说过  你是一个言出必行的人
You said you were a man of your word.
是的  没错
Oh, I am.
我只烧我的那一半
I'm only burning my half.
你们眼里只有钱
All you care about is money.
这个城市需要更高品味的罪犯
This town deserves a better class of criminal...
我就自己来填补下空缺吧
...and I'm gonna give it to them.
告诉你的手下  他们被我收编了
Tell your men they work for me now.
这是我的城市了
This is my city.
他们不会为一个怪物做事的
They won't work for a freak.
怪物
"Freak."
我们为何不把你切成碎块
Why don't we cut you up into little pieces...
然后拿来喂你的狗
...and feed you to your pooches? Hm?
然后我们就能看到饿狗到底有多忠诚了
And then we'll see how loyal a hungry dog really is.
这不是钱的问题
It's not about money...
是为了向人们传达一个信息
...it's about sending a message.
一切都将烧成灰烬
Everything burns.
-你是哪位  -我曾预见过...
- Who is this? - I had a vision...
一个没有蝙蝠侠的世界
...of a world without Batman.
黑帮们想尽法子赚些小钱
The Mob ground out a little profit...
而警察慢吞吞地一条街一条街的破案
...and the police tried to shut them down one block at a time.
简直无聊透顶
And it was so boring.
我改变主意了
I've had a change of heart.
我不希望瑞斯先生毁了这一切
I don't want Mr. Reese spoiling everything...
但也不能只让我一个人尽兴啊
...but why should I have all the fun?
也得给别人一点机会嘛
Let's give someone else a chance.
如果科尔曼·瑞斯在一小时内还没死
If Coleman Reese isn't dead in 60 minutes...
那我就炸掉一家医院
...then I blow up a hospital.
通知每个警察
Call in every officer.
让他们赶往距离最近的医院
Tell them to head to their nearest hospital
疏散人群并找到炸弹
and start evac and search.
通知运管部门  学校  监狱
Call the transit authority, school board, prisons.
把所有能用的巴士都调到医院
Get every bus down to a hospital.
重点监视哥谭中心医院
The priority is Gotham General.
立刻把那儿的所有人都撤出来
Wheel everybody out of that place right now.
你  你  还有你  跟我来
You, you and you, you come with me.
-我们去哪儿  长官  -去找瑞斯
- Where are we going, sir? - To get Reese.
我要你进系统  查查戈登的手下和他们的家人
I need you plugged in, checking Gordon's men and their families.
-查什么  -查住院登记
- Looking for? - Hospital admissions.
你要骑蝙蝠摩托去吗
Will you be wanting the Batpod?
大白天吗  那太高调了
In the middle of the day? Not very subtle.
那就开兰博基尼吧
The Lamborghini, then.
这样低调多了
Much more subtle.
借过  让我过去下  抱歉  好的
Excuse me. Let me through. Excuse me. Okay.
长官  您能帮帮我吗
Sir, could you help, please?
我要帮他找辆巴士
I'm gonna find a bus for him.
长官  局长  您真的认为...
Sir? Commissioner, do you really think...
会有普通市民要杀这个人吗
...an ordinary citizen would try to kill this man?
长官  局长
Sir. Commissioner.
把车开到后门
Get the cars around the back!
快走  继续拍  萨姆
Go. Keep rolling, Sam.
我看到布赖恩和理查德了
I see O'Brien and Richards.
他们没有亲属在哥谭的医院住院
No immediate family member admitted to a Gotham hospital.
-他们要杀我  -或许蝙蝠侠会来救你的
- They're trying to kill me. - Well, maybe Batman can save you.
戴维斯  有位子了  带他出来吧
Davis, they got space. Bring him out.
戴维斯
Davis.
我看到布恩斯和扎卡利了
I saw Burns and Zachary.
他们也没有
Nothing on them.
还有一个我不认识的巡警
And a patrolman I don't know.
好吧  现在怎么办
Okay, so, what now?
我们该怎么做  我们这是去哪儿
What do we do now? Where are we going?
把信息发给戈登
Send the information to Gordon.
当心
快离开这儿
Get out of here.
戴维斯
Davis.
护士小姐  我们要带他离开这儿
Ma'am, we're gonna have to move him now.
注意有家属
住院的警察
雷米兹 伯格
-你叫伯格  对吗  -是的  局长
- It's Berg, isn't it? - Commissioner.
你没事吧
You okay, son?
你知道吗
You know...
我可不希望我们之间有什么恩怨  哈维
...I don't want there to be any hard feelings between us, Harvey.
-当你和那个谁  -瑞秋
- When you and... - Rachel!
瑞秋一起被绑架时
Rachel were being abducted...
我还被关在戈登的牢房里呢
...I was sitting in Gordon's cage.
这事我可不能负责
I didn't rig those charges.
是你的人  你的计划
Your men, your plan.
我看上去像一个有计划的人吗
Do I really look like a guy with a plan?
你知道我是什么吗  我就是一条追逐汽车的狗
You know what I am? I'm a dog chasing cars.
我甚至不知道如果我追上了我该怎么办
I wouldn't know what to do with one if I caught it.
你知道吗  我只会做事
You know? I just do things.
黑帮有计划  警察有计划
The Mob has plans. The cops have plans.
戈登也有计划
Gordon's got plans.
知道吗  他们都是阴谋家
You know, they're schemers.
阴谋家都想掌控自己身边的小世界
Schemers trying to control their little worlds.
我不是阴谋家
I'm not a schemer.
我努力告诉这些阴谋家
I try to show the schemers...
他们想掌控事物的尝试是多么可悲
...how pathetic their attempts to control things really are.
所以  当我说  过来点
So when I say... Ah. Come here.
当我说你和你女朋友的事  不是我们的个人恩怨时
When I say that you and your girlfriend was nothing personal...
你会知道我说的都是实话
...you'll know that I'm telling the truth.
-我需要你把武器给我  -什么
- I'm gonna need your weapon. - What?
为什么  因为我妻子在住院吗
Why? Because my wife's in the hospital?
是的  这就是原因
Yeah, that'd be why.
是那些阴谋家让你成了现在这样
It's the schemers that put you where you are.
你曾经也是个阴谋家  你也有计划
You were a schemer, you had plans...
看看你现在的下场
...and look where that got you.
警方正竭尽全力防范
Police are taking every precaution...
劝阻人们不要贸然行事
...urging people not to take matters into their hands.
我只是做了我最擅长的事
I just did what I do best.
我拿了你的计划  反过来利用了它
I took your little plan and I turned it on itself.
看我把这座城市变成了什么样
Look what I did to this city
只是用了几个油桶和一点子弹
with a few drums of gas and a couple of bullets.
知道我注意到什么了吗
Hm? You know what I noticed?
当事情按计划发展时  没人会感到恐慌
Nobody panics when things go "According to plan."
即使计划本身充满了恐怖
Even if the plan is horrifying.
如果明天我告诉媒体
If tomorrow I tell the press that,
一个少年犯会被枪毙
like, a gangbanger will get shot...
或者一车的士兵会被炸上天
...or a truckload of soldiers will be blowing up...
没有人会恐慌
...nobody panics.
因为那都是计划的一部分
Because it's all part of the plan.
但是当我说一个上了年纪的市长会死
But when I say that one little old mayor will die...
那么每个人都会像发了疯一般
...well, then, everyone loses their minds.
引进一些无政府主义
Introduce a little anarchy...
扰乱一些既定秩序
...upset the established order...
一切就会陷入混乱
...and everything becomes chaos.
我就是混乱的使者
I'm an agent of chaos.
哦  你知道什么是混乱吗
Oh, and you know the thing about chaos?
就是公平
It's fair.
你活
You live.
你死
You die.
嗯哼  这样才像话嘛
Mmm. Now we're talking.
瑞斯先生
Mr. Reese.
是韦恩先生  对吧
That's Mr. Wayne, isn't it?
你做了一件非常勇敢的事情
That was a very brave thing you did.
你是说我闯了红灯吗
Trying to catch the light?
-你不是在保护这辆车吗  -为什么  谁在里面?
- You weren't protecting the van? - Why? Who's in it?
你不认为我应该去医院吗
Don't you think I should go to the hospital?
看来你没怎么留意新闻啊  韦恩先生?
Don't watch a whole lot of news, do you, Mr. Wayne?
东南方向
Southeast.
是哥谭中心医院
It's Gotham General.
-那座楼里的人都清空了吗  -是的
- Did you clear the building? - Yeah.
你们一定知道里面有多少人
You must know how many were inside.
你们有病人名单  一个个打电话
You have patient lists, roll call.
现在已经有50个人不见了   一辆巴士的人
Right now we're showing 50 people missing. One bus.
当时其他的巴士都离开了医院
The other buses were heading off to hospitals.
我猜只是漏数了一辆
I guess we missed one.
那你能不能也猜下哈维·登特在哪里
What's your guess about where Harvey Dent is?
继续寻找他的下落  别告诉别人
Keep looking. And keep it to yourself.
有人问起  就说我们已经救出他了
Anybody asks, we got him out.
帮我接通市长办公室
Get me the mayor's office on the line.
我们需要国家警卫队了
We're gonna need the National Guard.
依然有人员失踪
...People are still missing,
...包括哥谭有线频道的迈克·恩格尔
including GCN's own Mike Engel.
我刚收到通知
I'm now being told
现在插播本台刚刚收到的一段视频
that we're cutting to a video GCN has just received.
我是"今夜哥谭"的主持人迈克·恩格尔
I'm Mike Engel for Gotham Tonight.
"怎样才能让你们这些人参与进来呢
"What does it take to make you people wanna join in?
你们没能杀掉那个律师
You failed to kill the lawyer.
我得让你们动起来
I've gotta get you off the bench...
加入这场游戏  -动起来  游戏
- ...and into the game. - Bench. Game.
-夜幕降临时  城市就属于我  -我的
- Come nightfall, this city is mine. - Mine.
-留下来的人都要遵循我的规则  -规则
- And anyone left here plays by my rules. - Rules.
福克斯先生  安全系统显示有人入侵研发部的系统
Mr. Fox? Security is showing a break-in at the R & D Department.
如果你不想加入游戏
If you don't wanna be in the game...
-...现在就离开  -现在就离开
- ...get out now. - Get out now.
不过走大桥和隧道的人  肯定会碰到惊喜的
But the bridge-and-tunnel crowd are sure in for a surprise.
哈哈 哈哈"
Ha-ha, ha-ha."
哥谭警察已经关闭了...
Gotham P.D. Has shut down...
-上帝啊.  -...区域内的桥梁和隧道
- Sweet Jesus.... - the area's bridges and tunnels.
你不该出去看看吗  你知道  帮帮忙什么的
Shouldn't you be out there, you know, doing something?
今天我休息
It's my day off.
我去撒泡尿
I gotta take a leak.
帮我照看一下  好吗
Keep an eye out for me, will you?
怎么了  你还需要有人帮你把着吗
Now what? Need someone to shake it for you?
你好
Hello.
登特
Dent.
天哪  我还以为你死了呢
Jesus. I thought you was dead.
半死
Half.
是谁接走瑞秋的  乌尔茨
Who picked up Rachel, Wuertz?
-一定是马若尼的人干的  -闭嘴
- It must've been Maroni's men. - Shut up!
你是不是要告诉我你要保护...
Are you telling me that you're gonna protect
...戈登手下的另一个叛徒
the other traitor in Gordon's unit?
我不知道啊  他从没告诉过我
I don't know, he never told me.
登特  我对天发誓
Listen, Dent, I swear to God,
我真的不知道他们要对你怎么样
I didn't know what they were gonna do to you.
有意思...
That's funny...
因为我也不知道我到底会把你怎么样
...because I don't know what's gonna happen to you either.
很漂亮  是不是
Beautiful, isn't it?
是漂亮
Beautiful.
但不道德
Unethical.
还很危险
Dangerous.
你把哥谭的每台手机都变成了话筒
You've turned every cell phone in Gotham into a microphone.
和高频发送接收器
And a high-frequency generator-receiver.
你把我的声纳理论
You took my sonar concept
用在了城市里的每一部手机
and applied it to every phone in the city.
只要一半城市为声纳提供信号  你就可以监控整个哥谭了
With half the city feeding you sonar, you can image all of Gotham.
这是不对的
This is wrong.
我得找到这个人  卢修斯
I've gotta find this man, Lucius.
可代价又是什么呢
At what cost?
这个数据库已经加密了
The database is null-key encrypted.
只有一个人有权限去访问它
It can only be accessed by one person.
这样的权力对一个人来说太大了
This is too much power for one person.
所以我把它交给你
That's why I gave it to you.
只有你才能使用它
Only you can use it.
监听三千万人  这可不是我职责内容
Spying on 30 million people isn't part of my job description.
这是一个声音样本
This is an audio sample.
如果城市中任何一部手机捕获了他的声音
If he talks within range of any phone in the city...
你就能够锁定他的位置
...you can triangulate his position.
这次我就帮你
I'll help you this one time.
不过这也算是我的辞呈
But consider this my resignation.
只要这个机器还在韦恩企业一天  我就不会待下去
As long as this machine is at Wayne Enterprises, I won't be.
事情结束以后
When you're finished...
输入你的名字
...type in your name.
我的手下将会搜查每一个隧道每一座桥梁
My officers are going over every inch of the tunnels and bridges...
因为是小丑的威胁  我们别无选择
...but with the Joker's threat, they're not an option.
-那往东的陆路呢  -堵了好几个小时了
- And land routes east? - Backed up for hours.
只剩下能载三万人的渡轮了
Which leaves the ferries with 30,000 ready to board.
另外  我也想要用渡船把一部分罪犯运出岛去
Plus I wanna use the ferries so I can get some those prisoners off the island.
你和登特抓的那些囚犯吗  我担心的不是他们
The men you and Dent put away? Those aren't people I'm worried about.
你应该担心  无论小丑的计划是什么
You should be. Whatever the Joker's planning...
哈维抓的这些囚犯都很可能参与其中
...it's a good bet Harvey's prisoners are involved.
我想要把他们弄出去
I wanna get them out of here.
那么  哈维在哪里?
So where is Harvey?
-我们还没找到他  -天哪
- We haven't found him. - Oh, Jesus.
这个消息你还能隐瞒多久
How long can you keep this quiet?
碰到红灯  警察  都不要理会
Don't stop for lights, cops, nothing.
去见你老婆吗
Going to join your wife?
-你爱她吗  -是的
- You love her? - Yes.
你想像过听到她死讯的时候自己会什么样吗
You ever imagine what it would be like to listen to her die?
听着  这都是小丑造成的
Look, take it up with the Joker.
他杀了你的女人  他把你弄成...
He killed your woman. He made you...
...这个样子
...like this.
小丑不过是一条疯狗
The Joker's just a mad dog.
我要找的是放狗的人
I want whoever let him off the leash.
我干掉了乌尔茨
I took care of Wuertz,
但你在戈登组里的另一个人是谁
but who was your other man inside Gordon's unit?
谁接走瑞秋的  一定是一个她信任的人
Who picked up Rachel? Must have been someone she trusted.
你看  如果我告诉你...
Look, if I tell you...
你能不能放过我
...will you let me go?
可以给你机会
Can't hurt your chances.
是雷米兹
It was Ramirez.
-你说过的...  -我说过会给你机会的
- But you said... - I said it couldn't hurt your chances.
你真是个幸运的家伙
You're a lucky man.
-不过他不是  -谁?
- But he's not. - Who?
你的司机
Your driver.
后退
Stand back.
伙计  这可不对  我们应该上那条船的
Hey man, that ain't right. We should be on that boat.
你愿意和他们一起坐船吗  那请便
You wanna ride across with them? Be my guest.
长官  他们的引擎熄火了
Sir, they've stopped their engines.
好的  打开无线电
Right, get on the radio.
告诉他们  等我们把这群人渣放下之后  就回来接他们
Tell them we'll come back  and pick them up once we dump the scumbags.
自由号  这里是精神号  请回话
Liberty, this is Spirit. Come in.
这到底是怎么回事
What the heck was that?
怎么...
What the...?
自由号  请回话  这里是精神号  请回话
Liberty, come in, please. This is Spirit. Come in.
自由号  我们的情况一样  我们两台引擎都熄火了
Liberty, we have the same thing. We've lost both engines.
-自由号  请回话  -福克斯
- Liberty, come in. - Fox.
渡轮上面有情况
There's something going on on the ferries.
快下去引擎室看看
Get down to the engine room now.
老兄  出什么事儿了
Hey, buddy, what's happening?
船长  下面有上百个随时都可能爆炸的油桶  还有这个
Captain, we got a hundred barrels down there rigged to blow. And this.
哦  我的天哪
Oh, my God.
看起来像是某种引爆器
Looks like some kind of detonator.
为什么给我们自己船上炸弹的引爆器
Why would they give us the detonator to our own bomb?
今晚  你们都将成为一次社会实验的一分子
Tonight, you're all gonna be a part of a social experiment.
借助柴油和硝铵炸药的魔力
Through the magic of diesel fuel and ammonium nitrate...
我已经准备好了将你们都炸上天
...I'm ready right now to blow you all sky-high.
自由号  收到没有  完毕
Liberty, come in, over.
没有回复
It's dead.
如果有人试图下船的话  你们就都会死
If anyone attempts to get off their boat, you all die.
我在确定坐标
I'm zeroing in.
你们每艘船上都有一个另一艘船的引爆器
Each of you has a remote to blow up the other boat.
他的信号在渡轮上  但...
His voice is on the ferry, but...
...那不是源头
...but it's not the source.
西边
West.
-戈登  -我找到小丑的位置了
- Gordon. - I have the Joker's location.
普利维特大厦
Prewitt Building.
让你们的人在楼对面集合
Assemble on the building opposite.
到了午夜  我会把你们都炸飞
At midnight, I blow you all up.
不过  如果哪艘船先按了按钮
If, however, one of you presses the button,
我就让那艘船的人活
I'll let that boat live.
那么谁将会活下来呢
So who's it gonna be?
是哈维·登特最痛恨的罪犯们...
Harvey Dent's most-wanted scumbag collection...
...还是这些无辜的可爱市民
...or the sweet and innocent civilians?
你们来选择好了
You choose.
还有  你们最好快点做出决定
Oh, and you might wanna decide quickly...
因为另一条船上的人可没你们想象的那么高尚
...because the people on the other boat may not be quite so noble.
后退
Stay back.
好吧  凭什么由你们来决定
Well, now, who are you to decide?
我们至少应该全体讨论一下
We ought to talk this over, at least.
我们不应该死的  那些人才罪有应得
We don't all have to die. Those men had their chance.
我们不打算讨论这件事
We are not going to talk about this.
我们为什么不讨论这事
Why aren't we talking about it?
另一条船上的人也在讨论着一样的事情
They're talking over the same thing on the other boat.
-我们投票算了  -同意
- Let's put it to a vote. - Yes!
-你好  -是芭芭拉吗  我是安娜·雷米兹
- Hello? - Barbara, it's Anna Ramirez.
吉姆要你收拾一下  带上孩子们立刻离开那里
Jim needs you to pack up and put the kids in the car right away.
可是外面不是有警察么...
But the units outside...
那些警察已经不能相信了
Those cops can't be trusted.
吉姆要你尽快离开他们  越快越好
Jim needs you away from them as soon as possible.
我会让他们离开十分钟  你也得动作快点
I'll call them off for 10 minutes, and you'll have to move fast.
-可我带孩子们去哪里呢  -52街250号
- But where am I supposed to take them? - 250 52nd Street.
-巡逻车开走你就马上离开  -好的
- Leave as soon as the patrol car pulls out. - Okay.
她信了吗
She believe you?
那是因为她信任你
It's because she trusts you...
像瑞秋信任你一样
...just like Rachel did.
-我不知道...  -不知道他们会做什么
- I didn't know... - Didn't know what they'd do?
你是第二个对我这么说的警察了
You're the second cop to say that to me.
那你觉得他们到底会做什么
What exactly did you think they were gonna do?
他们威胁我  我妈妈的医院账单...
They got me early on. My mother's hospital bills...
-别说了  -对不起
- Don't! - I'm sorry.
你能接着活命了  警官
You live to fight another day, officer.
我们找到了医院失踪的那辆大巴
We found the missing hospital bus.
但我们需要解决人质问题
Then we have a hostage situation.
这简直是打靶啊
It's a shooting gallery.
他为什么要选有大窗户的地方
Why would he choose a spot with such big windows?
有五名小丑可一枪毙命
We have clear shots on five clowns.
狙击手干掉他们  打碎玻璃  小队从顶层降入
Snipers take them out, smash the windows, a team rappels in.
小队顺着楼梯井进入
Team moves in by the stairwells.
最多两到三人伤亡
Two, three casualties max.
-开始吧  -不会那么简单
- Let's do it. - It's not that simple.
有小丑在  永远不会那么简单
With the Joker, it never is.
简单的就是
What's simple is...
每过一秒  船上的人就离被炸飞更近一步
...every second, those people on the ferries get closer to blowing...
-那不会发生的  -那他就会把两艘船都炸飞
- That won't happen. - Then he'll blow both of them up!
我们没时间来做选票了
We don't have time for paper ballots.
请每个人  把自己的选择写在纸上
I want everybody to put their votes on this piece of paper.
有人带笔的话  互相传一传
If anyone's got pens, pass it along.
谢谢你  还有谁
Thank you. Anybody else?
麻烦传一下  还有谁  谢谢
Coming through. Anybody else? Thank you.
我们得把这些票尽快的收上来
We need to get these votes in quickly.
快点
Come on.
你还在等什么  按下按钮啊
What are you waiting for? Push the button!
我们没时间了
We're running out of time!
给我五分钟单独行动
I need five minutes alone.
不行  没时间了
No! There's no time!
我们能一枪毙命
We have clear shots!
登特也在那里  我们必须救出登特
Dent is in there with them. We have to save Dent!
我必须救出登特
I have to save Dent.
做好准备
Get ready.
两分钟之后我们开始行动
Two minutes, then we breach.
福克斯  传输图像
Fox, I need picture.
-喂?  -吉姆  我们有危险了
- Hello? - Jim, we're in trouble.
好的  α波段是第一人称视角
Okay, you got POV on alpha...
β波段是全景
...omni on beta.
看起来小丑们和人质分布在两个楼层
Looks like clowns and hostages on two floors.
在楼梯井上来的是一队特警
There's a SWAT team on the stairwell.
还有另一队特警在楼顶
Another SWAT team on the roof.
绳子准备好了
Line's clear.
-芭芭拉  冷静  -孩子在他手中
- Barbara, calm down. - He has the kids!
-你好  吉姆  -哈维?
- Hello, Jim. - Harvey?
-我的家人在哪里  -在我的家人死去的地方
- Where's my family? - Where my family died.
蓝色小队  锁定目标
Blue team, acquire the target.
突击队  安置爆破装置
Entry team, set your charge.
福克斯  特警弄错了狙击目标
Fox, the SWATs are targeting the wrong people.
这些小丑们才是人质
The clowns are the hostages.
红色小队  出发  红色小队  出发
Red team, go! Red team, go!
突击队  引爆  进入
Entry team, blow and go!
别动
Don't move.
开枪
Take the shot.
特警正在快速靠近
Those SWATs are coming in hot.
小丑们  放下武器
Clowns, put down your guns.
放下武器  趴在地上  快点
Drop your weapons! On the ground, now!
医生  趴下  清出射击空间  放下武器
Doctors, get down! Clear the line of fire. Drop your weap...
别动
Freeze!
不许动  否着...
Stand down or you will be...
向上看
Look up.
看到顶楼上的那些坏蛋了吗
See those bad guys on the floor above?
他们在等着伏击那些从电梯上去的特警
They're waiting to ambush the SWAT team coming up the elevator.
还有60秒
Sixty seconds.
140票反对  396票赞成
The tally is 140 against, 396 for.
那还等什么  按吧
So go ahead. Do it.
我们还在这儿
We're still here.
这说明他们也还没有选择杀掉我们
And that means they haven't killed us yet either.
前进  前进  前进
Go, go, go!
蓝色小队  掩护
Blue team, cover!
顶楼那儿有麻烦了
Trouble on the floor above.
马上趴到地上  快点
Get down on the ground now!
别动  否则我们会开枪的
Freeze! Stop or we will shoot.
我们会开枪的  放开那个警察
We will shoot you. Drop the officer.
快点把那个警察给放了
- Release the officer right now.
赶快放开他  跪下
Let him go now! On your knees!
我们抓到他了  他不会添乱了
We got him. He's out of the game.
- 把手举起来  - 从边上慢慢走过来
- Keep your hands in the air! - Step away from the edge!
停下
Halt!
趴下  不许动
Stay down! Don't move!
请注意  小丑们是人质  医生们才是目标
Be advised. Clowns are hostages, doctors are targets.
啊  你做到了  我好激动啊
Ah, you made it. I'm so thrilled.
-引爆器在哪儿  -去咬他
- Where's the detonator? - Go get him.
- 放下武器  - 不许动
- Put down your weapon! - Don't move!
你不想死
You don't wanna die...
但你更不知道怎样杀人
...but you don't know how to take a life.
给我好了
Give it to me.
反正这些人也会杀了你然后抢走它的
These men will kill you and take it anyway.
谁都不想弄脏了自己的手
No one wants to get their hands dirty.
好吧  我来
Fine. I'll do it.
那条船上的人  他们早就做出了选择
Those men on that boat? They made their choices.
他们选择了谋杀和偷窃
They chose to murder and steal.
我们没理由跟这群人一起死
It doesn't make any sense for us to have to die too.
这场景似曾相识啊
All the old familiar places.
稍等一下
Stand by.
红色小组  楼层安全  人质脱险
Red team, floor secure. Hostages are safe.
把它给我
Give it to me.
你可以告诉他们是我抢过来的
You can tell them I took it by force.
把它给我  我来完成你十分钟前就该做的事情
Give it to me, and I'll do what you should've did 10 minutes ago.
我们真的该消停一下
We really should stop this fighting,
否则我们就错过这场焰火了
otherwise we'll miss the fireworks.
不会有什么焰火的
There won't be any fireworks.
那我们等着瞧
And here we go.
你想要证明什么呢
What were you trying to prove?
以为每个人的内心  都像你一样丑陋吗
That deep down, everyone's as ugly as you?
你是孤身一人了
You're alone.
这年头真是谁都靠不住
Can't rely on anyone these days.
你什么事情都得自己来  不是吗
You gotta do everything yourself. Don't we?
没关系  我早有准备
That's okay. I came prepared.
我们生活的这个世界真是可笑  说到这
It's a funny world we live in. Speaking of which,
你知道我的疤是怎么来的吗
you know how I got these scars?
不  但我知道你的新疤是怎么来的
No, but I know how you got these.
哦  你啊
Oh, you.
你就是不能让我死  对吧
You just couldn't let me go, could you?
这就是  无坚不摧遇到坚不可摧
This is what happens when an unstoppable force...
的必然结果
...meets an immovable object.
你果真是不可撼动啊  是吗
You truly are incorruptible, aren't you?
嗯？  你不会杀我...
Huh? You won't kill me...
因为你的某种错位的自我正义感
...out of some misplaced sense of self-righteousness.
我也不会杀你
And I won't kill you...
因为与你斗真是其乐无穷
...because you're just too much fun.
我想你和我  注定要永远这样下去了
I think you and I are destined to do this forever.
你会永远被关在精神病院里
You'll be in a padded cell forever.
没准我们会同住一间病房呢
Maybe we could share one.
你知道吗  很快都得挤双人间了
You know, they'll be doubling up,
这座城市里精神失常的人会越来越多
the rate this city's inhabitants are losing their minds.
这座城市刚刚向你展示了
This city just showed you...
还是有很多人都坚信正义的
...that it's full of people ready to believe in good.
直到他们彻底崩溃那一刻
Until their spirit breaks completely.
直到他们发现真正的哈维·登特是怎样的人
Until they get a good look at the real Harvey Dent...
以及他的那些"英雄事迹"
...and all the heroic things he's done.
你不会认为  我会冒险把哥谭灵魂之战的成败
You didn't think I'd risk losing the battle for Gotham's soul...
寄托在跟你的肉搏上吧
...in a fistfight with you?
不
No.
你需要一张王牌在手
You need an ace in the hole.
我的王牌是哈维
Mine's Harvey.
你都干了什么
What did you do?
我带走了哥谭的光明骑士
I took Gotham's white knight...
并把他拉到了我们这个层次
...and I brought him down to our level.
那并不难  你看  疯狂  正如你所知
It wasn't hard. See, madness, as you know...
就像引力一样
...is like gravity.
你只需要轻轻一推
All it takes is a little push.
登特
Dent!
他们就是把她带到了这儿  戈登
This is where they brought her, Gordon,
在你的人把她交给他们后
after your men handed her over.
这就是她死去的地方
This is where she died.
我知道  当时我就在这里
I know, I was here...
-...要去救她  -但你没救出来
- ...trying to save her. - But you didn't.
- 我救不出她  -不  你本可以的
- I couldn't. - Yes, you could've.
如果你听了我的话
If you'd listened to me.
如果你站出来对抗腐败
If you stood up against corruption...
而不是和那些恶魔做交易
...instead of doing your deal with the devil.
我一直在努力打击黑帮
I was trying to fight the Mob!
如果你明白我失去什么  就不敢再这样狡辩了
You wouldn't dare try to justify yourself if you knew what I'd lost.
你有没有对自己最爱的人说过这样的话
Have you ever had to talk to the person you loved most...
告诉他们一切都会没事的  但你知道其实不会
...tell them it's gonna be all right, when you know it's not?
好了  你马上就要明白这是什么感觉了  戈登
Well, you're about to know what that feels like, Gordon.
然后你就可以看着我的眼睛对我说你很抱歉
Then you can look me in the eye and tell me you're sorry.
-你不会伤害我的家人的  -是啊
- You're not going to hurt my family. - No.
只是伤害你最爱的人而已
Just the person you love most.
那么  是你妻子吗
So is it your wife?
把枪放下  哈维
Put the gun down, Harvey.
哈维  放下枪
Harvey, put down the gun.
求你了  求你了  哈维
Please. Please, Harvey. Please.
哦  该死的
Oh, goddamn it.
你能不能别再用枪指着我家人
Will you stop pointing that gun at my family?
-不要  -我们选出来了
- No! - We have a winner.
不要  吉姆  拦住他
No, Jim, stop him!
-哈维  -别让他...
-Harvey. -Don't let him...
哈维
Harvey!
对不起
I'm sorry!
为所有的事
For everything.
请不要伤害我的儿子
Please don't hurt my son.
你把你的警察带过来了
You brought your cops?
他们只知道这里有情况
All they know is there's a situation.
他们不知道是谁  发生了什么  他们只是在周边设防
They don't know who or what. They're just creating a perimeter.
你觉得我想从这里逃走吗
You think I wanna escape from this?
这事根本无法逃避
There is no escape from this.
你不想伤害那孩子的  哈维
You don't wanna hurt the boy, Harvey.
这不是我想不想的事  这关系到公不公平
It's not about what I want, it's about what's fair!
你以为在这个混乱的时代我们还能做好人
You thought we could be decent men in an indecent time.
可是你错了
But you were wrong.
世界是残忍的  而残忍世界中的唯一道德准则...
The world is cruel. And the only morality in a cruel world...
...是运气
...is chance.
没有偏袒
Unbiased.
没有偏见
Unprejudiced.
公平
Fair.
他儿子的机会和瑞秋的一样多
His son's got the same chance she had.
一半一半
Fifty-fifty.
瑞秋的事并不是运气  是因为我们的行动
What happened to Rachel wasn't chance. We decided to act.
我们三个
We three.
那为什么是我  只有我一个人失去了一切
Then why was it me who was the only one who lost everything?
-不只是你  -小丑选择了我
- It wasn't. - The Joker chose me.
因为你是我们中最好的那个
Because you were the best of us.
他想要向世人证明即使是像你一样的好人...
He wanted to prove that even someone as good as you...
也会堕落
...could fall.
那么他是对的
And he was right.
你是那个拿着枪的人  哈维
You're the one pointing the gun, Harvey.
所以请把枪对准该为这些负责的人
So point it at the people responsible.
很公平
Fair enough.
你先来
You first.
轮到我了
My turn.
哈维  你是对的
Harvey, you're right.
瑞秋的死都是我的错
Rachel's death was my fault.
请不要惩罚我的孩子
Please don't punish the boy.
-惩罚我吧  -我正要这么做呢
- Please, punish me. - I'm about to.
和你儿子说一切都会没事的  戈登
Tell your boy he's gonna be all right, Gordon.
撒谎
Lie...
就像我那样
...like I lied.
一切都会没事的  儿子
It's going to be all right, son.
爸爸  爸爸  他还好吧
Dad? Daddy, is he okay?
-谢谢你  -你不必感谢我
- Thank you. - You don't have to thank me.
不  要谢
Yes, I do.
小丑赢了
The Joker won.
哈维的诉讼  他曾为之奋斗过的一切
Harvey's prosecution, everything he fought for...
都完了
...undone.
你给我们挽救城市的机会  也随哈维的名誉一起消亡了
Whatever chance you gave us at fixing our city dies with Harvey's reputation.
我们把一切都押在了他身上
We bet it all on him.
小丑毁灭了我们中最好的一个
The Joker took the best of us and tore him down.
人们会失去希望
People will lose hope.
他们不会的
They won't.
他们永远不会知道他做过什么
They must never know what he did.
五个人死了
Five dead.
两个是警察
Two of them cops.
-你没法掩盖这点  -是啊
- You can't sweep that... - No.
但不能让小丑赢
But the Joker cannot win.
哥谭需要它真正的英雄
Gotham needs its true hero.
-不  -你要么像英雄一样死去
- No. - You either die a hero...
要么就苟活下去  直到自己堕入恶人之伍
...or you live long enough to see yourself become the villain.
我能承担这些
I can do those things...
因为我不是英雄  不像登特
...because I'm not a hero, not like Dent.
是我杀了那些人  我可以是这样的人
I killed those people. That's what I can be.
不  不  不行  你不是这样的
No, no, you can't. You're not.
我可以是哥谭需要的任何样子
I'm whatever Gotham needs me to be.
叫人来吧
Call it in.
一位英雄
A hero.
不是我们值得拥有的  却是我们需要的英雄
Not the hero we deserved, but the hero we needed.
如同一位骑士一般
Nothing less than a knight...
闪耀光芒
...shining.
他们会追捕你
They'll hunt you.
你们会追捕我
You'll hunt me.
你们会谴责我
You'll condemn me.
放狗来咬我
Set the dogs on me.
因为事情必须如此
Because that's what needs to happen.
因为有时候
Because sometimes...
真相还远远不够
...the truth isn't good enough.
有时候人们应该得到更多
Sometimes people deserve more.
卢修斯·福克斯
有时候  人们的信念应该得到回报
Sometimes people deserve to have their faith rewarded.
蝙蝠侠
Batman.
Batman!
他为什么要跑  爸爸
Why's he running, Dad?
因为我们不得不追捕他
Because we have to chase him.
好了  我们进去  快  快  快走
Okay, we're going in! Go, go! Move!
他没有做什么坏事啊
He didn't do anything wrong.
因为他是哥谭应有的英雄
Because he's the hero Gotham deserves,
却不是它现在需要的英雄
but not the one it needs right now.
所以我们要追捕他
So we'll hunt him...
因为他能够承受这一切
...because he can take it.
因为他不是我们的英雄
Because he's not our hero.
他是一个沉默的卫士
He's a silent guardian...
一个警觉的保护者
...A watchful protector.
一个黑暗中的骑士
A dark knight.
蝙 蝠 侠 ： 黑 暗 骑 士
导演
克里斯托弗·诺兰
剧本
乔纳森·诺兰  及  克里斯托弗·诺兰
故事创作
克里斯托弗·诺兰  及  大卫·高耶
制片
艾玛·托马斯
查尔斯·罗文
制片
克里斯托弗·诺兰
根据DC漫画角色改编
蝙蝠侠形象作者
鲍勃·凯恩
执行制片
本杰明·梅尔尼克
迈克尔·E·尤斯兰
执行制片
凯文·德·拉·诺伊
托马斯·图尔
摄影
瓦利·菲斯特
艺术指导
内森·克劳利
剪辑
李·史密斯
配乐
汉斯·季默
詹姆斯·纽顿·霍华德
视觉特效
尼克·戴维斯
特效
克里斯·柯博德
服装设计
林迪·海明
选角导演
约翰·帕帕席德拉
克里斯蒂安·贝尔
迈克尔·凯恩
希斯·莱杰
加里·奥德曼
艾伦·艾克哈特
玛吉·吉伦哈尔
摩根·弗里曼
美国华纳兄弟影片公司 出品
美国传奇影业公司 联合出品
辛克匹影片公司 制作
克里斯托弗·诺兰 作品
谨以此片纪念
希斯·莱杰
康威·韦克利夫